<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Create a Fair Document">
   <intro>
      <description>
         This cheat sheet will show you how to create a <b>Fair Document</b> for documenting information about the People, Exhibits, and Livestock at an Animal Exposition.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="Show Tracker Perspective">
      <description>
         Open the <b>Tracker</b> perspective in the Workbench.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective(org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective.perspectiveId=com.verticon.tracker.product.desktop.perspective)"/>
   </item>
   <item
         skip="true"
         title="Create or Open a Project">
      <description>
         Create a new <b>Project</b> or Open an old <b>Project</b> in the Workbench.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.newWizard(newWizardId=org.eclipse.ui.wizards.new.project)"/>
   </item>
   <item title="Create New Fair Document" dialog="true">
      <description>
         File &gt; New &gt; <b>Fair Document</b>.<br/><br/>Then Select the parent project folder of the <b>Fair Document</b>.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.newWizard(newWizardId=com.verticon.tracker.fair.editor.presentation.FairModelWizardID)"/>
   </item>
   
   <item title="Choose Fair Root Entry" dialog="true">
      <description>
         You will be prompted for the root <b>Fair</b> Model Object to create.<br/><br/>Choose <b>Fair</b> element in the drop down list.
      </description>
      
   </item>
  
   <item title="Load a Premises Document Resource">
      <description>
         The <b>Fair</b> Editor is a composite document editor.  It manages the edits for both a <b>Fair Document</b> resource and an associated <b>Premises Document</b> resource.<br/><br/>
         In the instance of the <b>Fair Editor</b> where the new <b>Fair Document</b> is displayed, right mouse click on the entry showing the document name to show the popup menu.<br/><br/>
 		 Select the <b>Load Resource</b> menu item and browse for a <b>Premises Document</b> to associate with this <b>Fair Document</b>.<br/><br/>
      	 You should now see a <b>Premises Document</b> showing in the editor below the <b>Fair Document</b>.<br/><br/>
      	 You can view, edit and manipulate this <b>Premises Document</b> like a normal <b>Premises Document</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
   
   <item title="Show Properties View">
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=org.eclipse.ui.views.PropertySheet)"/> 
      <description>
          To edit the entries in a <b>Fair Document</b> open the <b>Properties</b> view. 
      </description>
   </item>
   
    <item title="Document Fair Details">
      <description>
         Tracker Editors show documents as trees of parent and child entries.<br/><br/>
         Selecting entries in the Editor trees will display their details in the <b>Properties</b> view.<br/><br/>
         In the instance of the <b>Fair Editor</b> where the new <b>Fair Document</b> is displayed, unfold the entry showing the document name and select the root <b>Fair</b> entry.<br/><br/>
 		 In the <b>Properties</b> view you can now enter or change the properties of the <b>Fair</b> entry.<br/><br/>
		 Note the <b>Fair Premises</b> attribute.  The drop down will show the loaded <b>Premises Document</b>.  Select it.
      </description>
   </item>
   
   <item title="Show People View">
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=com.verticon.tracker.fair.views.PeopleView)"/> 
      <description>
          Open the <b>People</b> view to add <b>People</b> to the <b>Fair Document</b>.<br/><br/>
      </description>
   </item>
   
   <item title="Add People">
      <description>
The <b>People</b> view is a composite master-detail view of the <b>Young People</b> and <b>Adults</b>associtated with the <b>Fair</b>. <br/><br/>
Like the <b>Properties</b> view you can use this view to see and edit details about <b>People</b>.  You can also use this view to sort, filter, and navigate through all <b>People</b> in the <b>Fair Document</b>.<br/><br/>
Select the green + in the toolbar of the <b>People</b> view to add <b>People</b> to the <b>Fair</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
   
   <item title="Show Exhibits View">
      <description>
      Once you have added one or more <b>People</b> you can associate them with <b>Exhibits</b>.  Open the <b>Exhibits</b> view to add <b>Exhibits</b> to a hierarchy of <b>Lot-Class-Department-Division</b> entries in the <b>Fair Document</b>.<br/><br/>
	  </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=com.verticon.tracker.fair.views.ExhibitsView)"/>
   </item>
   
   <item title="Add Exhibits">
      <description>
     	Like the <b>People</b> view the <b>Exhibits</b> view is a master-detail view of all the <b>Exhibits</b> in the <b>Fair</b>.<br/><br/>
 		Use this view to add details, filter, and navigate through all <b>Exhibits</b> in the <b>Premises Document</b>.
      	Select the green + in the toolbar of the <b>Exhibits</b> view to add <b>Exhibits</b> to the <b>Fair</b>.
      </description>
        </item>
   <item
         title="Save Document">
      <description>
        Once your done editing the save the file.<br/><br/>
		File &gt; Save <br/><br/>         
        To save the <b>Fair Document</b> to Disk.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.file.save"/>
   </item>
  
</cheatsheet>
