<?xml version="1.0"?>
<webpage id="faqs">
	<config param="rcsdate" value="$Date: 2010-09-27 14:44:13 -0500 (Mon, 27 Sep 2010) $" />
	<head>
		<title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
		<summary>Tracker FAQs
		</summary>
		<keywords>livestock, open source, NAIS, XML, Eclipse, RFID,
			herd management faq
		</keywords>
	</head>

		<qandaset >
		   <qandadiv><title>Project Status</title>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Q: What is the status of the Project?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
				    <para>A: The project is in beta testing stage (milestone 0.5.0) at this time.</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Q: Is the project accepting new beta testers at this time?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>A: Yes.  Please send us an email  
					<userinput><email>support@verticon.com</email>
					with the subject
					<command>[Tracker] Beta Testing</command> </userinput> </para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
		</qandadiv>
		
	<qandadiv><title>Installation</title>
		
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Q: What OS platforms are supported?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>A: Currently versions for Windows and Linux are supported.</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
			
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Q: Is an Apple version of the software planned?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>A: Yes, but it is not deployed to the download sites at this time.</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
	</qandadiv>
	
	<qandadiv><title>Getting Started</title>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Q: I have installed the software what do I do next?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>A: It is always best to read the documentation first. Did you already do this? 
					If not start with the <ulink uri="http://help.eclipse.org/helios/nav/0">Eclipse Workbench User Guide</ulink> and
					then read the <olink targetdoc="docs" targetptr="userGuide">Tracker User Guide</olink>.</para>
					<para>Note that <emphasis>both of these documents are available from within the Tracker.</emphasis>
					 Go to the <userinput> <command>Help</command> > <command>Help Contents</command> </userinput>
					 to show the built in Help Documentation.</para> 
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Q: When I first start the Tracker I get a Welcome Screen. What should I do?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>A: Click into the various icons to view the contents of the Welcome information. 
					Then go to first steps page and provision the tool.</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
			
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Q: Why do I have to provision the software after install?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>A: Tracker BI Toolkit is a component container that is customizable by the end user.
					You can select and provision the Tracker Toolkit only with the features to meet your needs.</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
		
	</qandadiv>
	
	<qandadiv><title>iRouter</title>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Q: What is the relationship between the Tracker BI Toolkit and the iRouter?</para>
				</question>
				
				<answer>
					<para>A: Tracker BI Toolkit is a container for tool features.  When it is first installed it is empty.
					For the Tracker BI Toolkit to be useful the user must select and install the tool features they require. 
					The iRouter is one of the many Tracker tool features that can be installed. The end user can select and 
					install iRouter features by itself or with a combination of any of the other 
					Tracker livestock information management tool features.
					</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
		
	</qandadiv>
	<qandadiv><title>Custom Use Cases</title>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Q: I am not in the US can I still use Tracker?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>A: Yes, although the Tracker Professional Services and Component Development Teams will 
					have to craft a data model and editor feature for your use case.</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
			<qandaentry>
				<question>
					<para>Q: Is Tracker Internationalized?</para>
				</question>
				<answer>
					<para>A: Tracker is not internationalized in milestone3 but will be as part of the beta program.</para>
				</answer>
			</qandaentry>
		</qandadiv>
	</qandaset>
</webpage>
