<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DockBook XML V4.5//EN" 
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
	<?dbhtml filename="premisesEditor/premisesEditor.html" ?>
	<title>Premises Editor</title>
	
    <section id="overview">
  	<?dbhtml filename="overview/premisesEditorOverview.html" ?>
	<title>Overview</title>

	<section id="overviewWhatIs">
		<title>What is the Premises Editor?</title>
		<para>
		The Premises Editor is a comprehensive open desktop solution for documenting and managing 
        livestock premises, animal life data, and animal event history information.</para>
	</section>

    <section id="overviewGoals">
        <?dbhtml filename="overview/premisesEditorOverview_goals.html" ?>
		<title>Project Goals</title>
		<para>
			The Premises Editor project was undertaken to provide;
			<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A simple to use editor for creating premises, animal and event history 
						documentation for livestock producers and infrastructure providers;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A low cost, yet extensible documentation solution to meet the needs of both large and
						small scale livestock operations;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						An industry standard document format for livestock premises information,
						animal life data and animal event history inter-exchange.
					</para>
				</listitem>

			</orderedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="overviewFunctionaldesc">
	     <?dbhtml filename="overview/premisesEditorOverview_functionalDescription.html" ?>
		<title>Functional Overview</title>
		<para>
			The Premises Editor is a tool to create and edit Tracker Premises document. Premises documents
			specify Premises details, animal life data and animal event histories.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			Premises details are manually added to premises documents by the user, but Animal life data
			 and Event histories can be added to Tracker Premises Documents;
			<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
				<listitem>
					<para>
						As individual animals by the user of the Premise Editor, using either the form based
						Premises Views or with the generic Properties Viewer;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						In bulk, by importing lists of animals, through Tracker's Bulk Event Processing Utilities;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						In real time, from tag ID readers, through the Tracker Readers Feature.
					</para>
					<para>
					    See the following section <link linkend="editingPremisesDocuments">Editing Premises Documents</link> for details on
					    Tracker Readers Feature and Premises document editing.
					</para>
				</listitem>

			</orderedlist>
		</para>
		<note><para>The Premises Editor comes with a set of predefined event types 
		that are suitable for documenting most livestock histories. For recording unique premises specific 
		events, the Premises Editor also provides a facility to define custom event types. Once defined, these
		custom event types can be used along with the predefined event types to record animal histories. 
		</para></note>
		</section>
	</section>

   <section id="creatingPremisesDocuments">
    	<?dbhtml filename="creatingPremisesDocuments/creatingPremisesDocuments.html" ?>
		<title>Creating Premises Documents</title>
		<para>
			This section will walk you through a few simple steps for the creation of an example Premises document. 
		</para>
		<para>
			If you haven't done so, create a project first. From the 'File' menu select 'New'
			and 'Project' and give it the name 'test'.
		</para>

			<figure id="fig_newProject">
				<title>Create a new Project</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../images/gettingStarted/chooseProject.png" />
						</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
			</figure>

		<para>
			Creation of new project artifacts like files and documents follow the same pattern as the creation of 
			the project. From the 'File' menu select 'New' then select 'Premises Document'.  Take the default 
			name for the document and place it under the project folder named 'test'.
			<xref linkend="fig_newPremisesDocument" /> shows the screens for creating a Premises document.
		</para>

		<figure id="fig_newPremisesDocument">
				<title>Create a new Premises Document</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../images/gettingStarted/createPremises.png" />
						</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
			Your workspace should now look something like 
			<xref linkend="fig_createdPremisesDocument" />.  If you don't see the Properties View in lower
			part of the desktop, select the Premises element, right click, and from the popup menu select
			the last entry 'Show Properties View'.
		</para>

		<figure id="fig_createdPremisesDocument">
				<title>A new Premises Document</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../images/gettingStarted/createdPremises.png" />
						</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>
			The 'Properties View' is a generic editor for all document elements<footnote><para>
			Any Tracker document element once selected, can be edited with the 'Properties View'.</para></footnote>.  
			You can use it to add, delete or replace element attributes.  To edit an elements properties in 
			the 'Properties View', select it first in an editors 'Selection' window.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			In addition to the main 'Selection' editor, the Premises editor offers three form editors
		    to edit Premises, Policy, Location, and Area elements and their attributes. 
		    <xref linkend="fig_GettingStartedEditingPremisesElement" /> shows the 'Premises' form editor in 
		    contrast with the generic 'Properties View'<footnote><para>Either the form editors or the 'Properties View'
		    may be used for editing.</para></footnote>.
		</para>
		<figure id="fig_GettingStartedEditingPremisesElement">
				<title>Premises Form Editor</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../images/gettingStarted/editingPremises.png" />
						</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	   
	</section>
	
	<section id="editingPremisesDocuments">
    	<?dbhtml filename="editingPremisesDocuments/editingPremisesDocuments.html" ?>
		<title>Editing Premises Documents</title>
		<section id="editingPremisesDocuments_choosingPremieseEditor">
			<title>Two Types of Editor</title>
			<para>
			Two types of editors are used to manipulate Premises and Animal
			Documents<footnote><para>Premises and Animal documents
			created or edited in one editor type can later be opened and edited with 
			the other.</para></footnote>, Premises Editor and Premises Transaction Editor as shown in
			<xref linkend="fig_choosePremisesEditor" />.   
			</para>

		<figure id="fig_choosePremisesEditor">
			<title>Choosing a Premises Editor type to Open a Premises Document</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/navigation/openDocumentWith.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>
			<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
				<listitem>
					<para>The Premises Editor is the default editor.  It is the editor
						that is opened when a document is created.  The Premises Editor
						is used for creating, manipulating, navigating and interpreting 
						Premises and Animal Documents when there is no requirement for 
						interfacing with external devices.<footnote>
						<para>The Premises Editor also provides user friendly forms based 
						editors for editing Premises, Policy, Location,
						and Area elements and attributes.  These form based editors are not
						supported in the Premises Transaction Editor. So with the Premises 
						Transaction Editor the Properties View will have to be used to edit these
						elements and their attributes.</para></footnote></para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The Premises Transaction Editor can be used in a similar way to 
					the Premises Editor, but it has additional functionality to support 
				    the interfacing with external devices like RFID tag readers.
					<note><title>Reader Feature</title>
					<para>The Readers Feature is an optional Feature that may be installed 
					(called <glossterm>provisioned</glossterm>) by the user. The Readers Feature
					allows the Tracker <acronym>BI</acronym> Toolkit User to control and configure connections to one or more 
				    Tag ID Event Readers enabling them to independently add Event Transactions to 
					Premises Documents.</para>
					</note>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>

		<note>
			<para>
				Both the Premises Editor and the Premises Transaction Editor can be used for bulk event
				processing. For more information on bulk even processing see
				<xref linkend="chBulkEventProcessing" />.
			</para>
		</note>
		</section>
	
	    <section id="editingPremisesDocuments_complementaryViews">
	    <?dbhtml filename="editingPremisesDocuments/editingPremisesDocuments_complementaryViews.html" ?>
	    	<title>Complementary Views</title>
	    	<para>
			The Premises Editor is complemented by several Eclipse and Premises Editor Feature 
			Specific views, each giving the user a unique way to <emphasis>view and edit</emphasis> 
			the information in a Premises Document. Selecting information in the Premises Editor 
			will synchronize selections in complementary views
			as shown in <xref linkend="fig_editorAndOutline"/>.
		</para>
		<figure id="fig_editorAndOutline">
                <title>Premises Editor Synchronized with Views
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/navigation/editorAndOutline.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
		<para>The <ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-30.htm">
			<citetitle>Outline View</citetitle></ulink> is synchronized with selections in the
			Premises Editor and the 
			<ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-29.htm">
			<citetitle>Properties View</citetitle></ulink>. By selecting an element
			in the Outline View, that Element is also selected in Premises Editor
		    and it's attributes are visualized in the Properties View.
		</para>
		
		<para>Premises Editor selections are also synchronized with the Premises
		 specific Animals view and Events views. These two views provide a <emphasis>
		 master-detail view of information in Premises documents.</emphasis>
		</para>
		<para>
				For more information on master details views see
				<xref linkend="masterDetailViews" />.
		</para>
		
		<note>
			<para>
				The Tracker Model Editor also supports an advanced element selection
				and query functionality, for details see <emphasis>Tracker OCL Query Feature</emphasis>.
			</para>

		</note>
	    </section>
		
		
		<section id="editingPremisesDocuments_enteringDateTime">
			<?dbhtml filename="editingPremisesDocuments/editingPremisesDocuments_enteringDateTime.html" ?>
			<title>Entering Date and Time</title>
			
			<para>
			When using the forms based editors to change date times, clicking on the text entry field of an attribute
			that is a DateTime should bring up a 'Date Time Picker' dialog.  <xref linkend="fig_dateTimePickerDialog" /> 
			shows the Date Picker Dialog that was visualized after the user clicked on the Animal Birth Date text 
			field in the details pane<footnote><para>The next section discusses Master Details Views.</para></footnote> 
			of the Animals View.
		</para>

		<figure id="fig_dateTimePickerDialog">
				<title>Date and Time Picker Dialog</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center"
							fileref="../images/masterDetail/animalBirthDate.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
		</figure>
			<para>When manually entering Dates<footnote >
				<para>The Animal BirthDate value is the only Date value that can be set to null by entering the text <userinput>0-0-0</userinput> 
				in the Properties view or the Animals view. </para>
				</footnote>  
				and DateTime attribute values in Premises documents the following formating patterns are determinative:<table frame='all'>
				<title>Format Patterns for Text Entry</title>
				<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
					<colspec colname='c1' />
					<colspec colname='c2' />
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>Format Pattern</entry>
							<entry>Example</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry>yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ss'.'SSSZ</entry>
							<entry>2007-11-12T00:00:00.000-0600</entry>
						</row>
						
						<row>
							<entry>yyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ss'.'SSS</entry>
							<entry>2007-11-12T00:00:00.000</entry>
						</row>
						
						<row>
							<entry>yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ss</entry>
							<entry>2007-11-12T00:00:00</entry>
						</row>
						
						<row>
							<entry>yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm</entry>
							<entry>2007-11-12T00:00</entry>
						</row>

					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</table>
			</para>
		</section>

	</section>

    <section id="masterDetailViews">
      <?dbhtml filename="masterDetailViews/masterDetailViews.html" ?>
		<title>Master Detail Views</title>
		<para>A master detail view is one where a master element
	    and its related detail attributes are shown on the same view.</para>
	    <para>
	    The master element is depicted as a row in a table of other master elements 
	    derived from the document.  Columns can be rearranged by dragging the column headers 
	    to the desired location and
	    master elements in the table can be sorted by clicking on the column header to use as
	    a sort key.  Clicking a  second time will sort in the opposite direction. 
	    </para>
	    
	    <para>
	    The Detail attributes are depicted within a form. The detail attributes in form may 
	    consist of read-write and read-only attributes. The detail attributes are displayed 
	    based on the current element row selection in the master table.</para>
	    
	    <para>A master detail view can be displayed with a horizontal layout as shown in <xref 
		linkend="fig_animalsView-horizontal"/> or with a vertical layout as shown in <xref 
		linkend="fig_animalsView-vertical"/>. 
	    </para>
	    
	    <figure id="fig_animalsView-horizontal">
                <title>Animals View Horizontal Layout
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/masterDetail/animalsView-horizontal.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        
        <figure id="fig_animalsView-vertical">
                <title>Animals View Vertical Layout
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/masterDetail/animalsView.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
        </figure>
		
		<para>Elements displayed in the master table can be filtered by entering characters in the text 
		field and the attribute selection control.  <xref linkend="fig_animalsView-filtered"/> shows the 
		list of Animals filtered to display only Male animals. 
	    </para>
	    
	    <figure id="fig_animalsView-filtered">
                <title>Animals View Filtered Master Elements
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/masterDetail/animalsView-filtered_sex.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        
		<para>Using the fourth button in the view menu, attributes displayed in the detailed form can be 
		filtered to show only basic attributes. <xref linkend="fig_animalsView-basicProperties"/> shows the
		effect of deselecting the 'Show Advanced Properties' button. 
	    </para>
	    
	    <figure id="fig_animalsView-basicProperties">
                <title>Animals View Filtered Detail Attributes
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/masterDetail/animalsView-basicProperties.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        
		<section id="masterDetailViews_animals">
		<?dbhtml filename="masterDetailViews/masterDetailViews_animals.html" ?>
		<title>Animals View</title>
		<para><xref 
		linkend="fig_animalsView"/> is a master detail view of the Animals Elements in the Premise 
		document being edited in the Premises Editor.
		Selections in the Premises Editor will synchronize downward to selections in the master table
		of the the Animals view.  Selections in the master table of the Animals View will synchronize 
		upward to the Premises Editor and the Outline View.</para>
		
		<figure id="fig_animalsView">
                <title>Animals View
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/masterDetail/animalsView.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
        </figure>
		
		</section>
		
		<section id="masterDetailViews_events">
		<?dbhtml filename="masterDetailViews/masterDetailViews_events.html" ?>
		<title>Events View</title>
		<para><xref 
		linkend="fig_eventsView"/> is a master detail view of the Events Elements in the Premise 
		document being edited in the Premises Editor.
		Selections in the Premises Editor will synchronize downward to selections in the master table
		of the the Events view.  Selections in the master table of the Events View will synchronize 
		upward to the Premises Editor and the Outline View.</para>
		<figure id="fig_eventsView">
                <title>Events View
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/masterDetail/eventsView.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
        </figure>
		</section>
	</section>
			
	<section id="chBulkEventProcessing">
	 <?dbhtml filename="bulkProcessing/premisesBulkEventProcessing.html" ?>
	<title>Bulk Event Processing</title>
	
	<section id ="chbulkEventProcessing_newEventsAndAnimals">
	  <?dbhtml filename="bulkProcessing/premisesBulkEventProcessing_newEventsAndAnimals.html" ?>
		<title>Bulk Loading New Events and Animals</title>
		<para>Although Premises Editors make it easy to add individual animals and 
		events to Premises Documents, individually adding dozens of animals, or hundreds of events 
		to a Premises is not practical. For bulk loading of animals and events, Premises Editors
	    use Animal Document Templates, Tag IdNumber files and event manipulation wizards to simplify 
	    the process.</para>
		<para>Like Premises Documents, Animal Document Templates are document files created by 
		Premises Editor Document Creation Wizards. Think of Animal Documents as containing some but not 
		all the information that is in a Premises Document. Specifically a Animal Document is a Premises 
		Document that only contains a single animal. Like an animal in the Premises Document, an Animal 
		Document Template can contain a tag with an associated set of events. Animal Document Templates 
		serve as a way to represent an event or a set of events that can then be applied to one or more 
		specified animals in a Premises Document.</para>
		<para>Within a Premises Document you can specify which animals to apply the events contained 
		in the Animal Document Template by:<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
				<listitem>
					<para>Directly selecting the animal or a set of animals in the Premises Document 
					with mouse	selections.<tip>
							<para>
								One or more animals in the Premises
								Document can also be selected with
								<acronym>OCL</acronym>
								Query operations. See <emphasis>OCL Query Feature</emphasis> for details.
							</para>
						</tip>
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					Indirectly selecting an animal or set of animals in the Premises Document from 
					lists of Tag/@idNumbers contained in Tag IdNumber files. 
					See<xref linkend="chBulkEventProcessing_IdNumberFiles" />
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="chbulkEventProcessing_animalTemplates">
	    <?dbhtml filename="bulkProcessing/premisesBulkEventProcessing_animalTemplates.html" ?>
		<title>Animal Document Templates</title>
		<para>
			Animal Document Templates are files that representative a single animal and a set of 
			associated events.  Tracker event modification wizards<footnote>
						<para>Event modification wizards are accessible through popup menus on specific 
						Tracker document elements and File Resources.</para>
						</footnote>
			and Animal Document Templates allow the Tracker user
			to add various combinations of animals and/or events to Premises Documents.
		</para>
		<para>
			Animal Document Templates have the following characteristics;
			<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
			    <listitem>
					<para>
						Animal Document Templates are persisted as file resources with a 
						*.animal extension;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Animal Document Templates contain a default Animal, a Tag and a set of 
						representative events;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If a Tag is included as a child element of the Animal Element, the Tag/@idNumber 
						is not considered significant and is ignored;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Representative Events in Animal Document Templates are significant and will 
						be copied to specified Animal or set Animals in the Premises Document;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Date Time attributes of Animal Document Templates Events are considered 
						significant dates, if the Date Time value is a date after the year 2000. These 
						attributes are copied to the Event Elements that are added to the 
						Premises Document. 
					 </para>
					 <para>
						When using 
			            <link linkend="chBulkEventProcessing_IdNumberFiles">tagIdNumber Files</link>
			            with date encoded names, 
						Date Time attributes of Animal Document Templates Events are considered 
						reference dates if the Date Time value of the Templated Event is a date 
						before the year 2000. These attributes are changed to the date encoded in the 
						name of the tagIdNumber file before being copied to the Event Elements that 
						are added to the Premises Document. 
					 </para>
					 
					 <note>
							<para>
								When Events are added to Premises 
								Documents using Tracker Readers feature, the 
								Date Time attributes of the Events 
							    added to the Premises Document will always have the 
								Date Time attributes set to the current time.
							</para>
					</note>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="chBulkEventProcessing_IdNumberFiles">
		<?dbhtml filename="bulkProcessing/premisesBulkEventProcessing_tagIdNumberFiles.html" ?>
		<title>Tag IdNumber Files</title>
		<para>
			Commercial tag readers typically transmit animal id numbers to computers as
			<acronym>ASCII</acronym>
			encoded characters (For more information on ASCII, see the Wikipedia entry for
			<ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASCII">
				<citetitle>ASCII</citetitle>
			</ulink>
			). Tag Readers send this data to computers over serial communication ports or 
			Bluetooth network connections. 
			<note>
				<para>
					In the Premises Data Model, the Tag id Numbers are represented as  
					<code>Tag/@idNumber</code> attributes.
				</para>
			</note>
			A generic way to handle serial and/or Bluetooth tag id number transmissions 
			is to setup the receiving computer's communication facility to capture this data 
			as text files.  Capture files containing <acronym>ASCII</acronym> numbers that 
			are saved with a *.tags extension are identified as
			<emphasis>Tag IdNumber Files.</emphasis>
		</para>
		<para>
			To indicate to Premises Editor that the read time of the tags in a Tag IdNumber 
			file is significant, the name of the tag file may be formated to reflect that time. 
			To timestamp a Tag IdNumber file use the formating of
			<code>yyMMddHHmmss</code>
			, where
			<simplelist type='horiz' columns='1'>
				<member>yy is the last two digits of the year,</member>
				<member>MM is the month,</member>
				<member>dd is the day of the month,</member>
				<member>
					HH is the hour of the day in 24 hour clock,
				</member>
				<member>mm is the minute of the hour,</member>
				<member>ss is the second</member>
			</simplelist>
			<example>
				<title>A Time Stamped Tag IdNumber File Name</title>
				<formalpara>
					<title>060409131111.tags</title>
					<para>
						Specifies the date of all
						<code>Tag/@idNumber</code>
						reads to have occurred at 2006-04-09T13:11:11.
					</para>
				</formalpara>
			</example>
			<note>
			  <para>
				  To use the Time Stamped Tag IdNumber File Names the dates of  
				  the events in an Animal Document Template must be set 
				  to date times earlier than the 2000 AD reference. 
			  </para>
			</note>
		</para>
		<tip>
			<para>
				Tag IdNumber Files can also be utilized by the Reader Feature.
			</para>
		</tip>
	</section>
	
	<section id="chBulkEventProcessing_usageAndOperations">
		<?dbhtml filename="bulkProcessing/premisesBulkEventProcessing_usageAndOperations.html" ?>
		<title>Usage and Operations</title>
		
		<section id="chBulkEventProcessing_usageAndOperations_addEventsToAnimals">
			<title>Adding Events to Manually Selecting Animals</title>
			<para>
				To add a series of events to an animal or set of animals in a Premises 
				Document select the animal or animals and invoke a popup menu item;
				<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Right click on the Animal to get the top level popup menu;
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select the 'Tracker' menu item to get the Tracker popup menu;
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select 'Add Template Events to Selected Animals' to bring up a 
							selection window to select a Template;
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Choose an Animal Document Template containing the set of events 
							you wish to add the animal.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section id="chBulkEventProcessing_usageAndOperations_addEventsAnimalsToListofTagIds">
			<?dbhtml filename="bulkProcessing/premisesBulkEventProcessing_addEventsOrAnimals.html" ?>
			<title>
				Add Events and/or Animals to a List of Animals Specified in a File
			</title>
			<para>
				To add a series of events and/or animals to the Premises as a whole, you 
				will still need to specify which animals to add event to.  This can be 
				done indirectly with a Tag IdNumber file. Select a Tag IdNumber file and 
				invoke a popup menu item it.
				<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Right click on the Animal Document Template that contains the 
							list of animal ids which specify the set of animals in the 
							Premises Document that you wish to add events to.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							From the popup menu Select 'Tracker' to get the Tracker specific menu.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select 'Add Template Events to Premises' to bring up a selection 
							window that will allow you to select a Animal Document Template.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Choose an Animal Document Template containing the set of template 
							events and the default animal type you wish to add the file 
							specified animals in the premises.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	</section>
    
	<section id="premisesDocuments">
		<?dbhtml filename="model/premisesEditorModel_premisesDocuments.html" ?>
		<title>Premises Documents</title>
		<para>Whether it is word processing documents, spreadsheet documents, or presentation 
			documents, today's computer users are most familiar with software applications that 
			create and manipulate documents that describe specific instances of information.</para>
		<para>The Premises Editor enables users to create, transform and edit Livestock 
			Premises documents that represent Animal Premises. The attributes of the premises, 
			the animals in the premises and the events associated with these animals are specified in 
			Premises documents.</para>
		<para>Premises document files utilize a .premises file extension to distinguish them 
		from other types of files.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="premisesDataModel">
	<?dbhtml filename="model/premisesEditorModel_dataModel.html" ?>
	<title>Premises Data Model</title>
	<para>
		Because all user activity centers around the creation and manipulation
		of
		<emphasis>Premises Documents</emphasis>, understanding the structure 
		(called the <glossterm>data model</glossterm>) 
		of Premises documents is the easiest way to learn to use the information management facilities of
		the Premises Editor.
	</para>
	<section id="premisesDataModel_corePremisesElements">
	    <?dbhtml filename="model/premisesEditorModel_dataModel_core.html" ?>
		<title>Data Model Core Elements</title>
	<para>
		All Premises documents structurally conform to the
		<emphasis>Premises Data Model</emphasis>. In the Premises Data Model,
		a single Premises contains zero or more animals. Each Animal must have at 
		least one but may have more than one (identification) tag. Each Tag must 
		have at least one but may have more than one associated event.
	</para>
	<para>
		Core elements of the Premises Data Model are shown in
		<xref linkend="fig_coreDataModel1" />.
	</para>
	<figure id="fig_coreDataModel1">
		<title>Premises Data Model Core Elements</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/model/coreDataModel3.png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
		
		<para>
			<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
				<listitem>
					<para>The core elements of the Premises Model are depicted as rectangles in the figure.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The notation within the elements are the attributes of the element.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The notation between the elements are the relationships of the elements.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
		<para>The following table offers a text explanation of the primary element relationships.<table frame='all'>
				<title>Core Elements of the Premises Model</title>
				<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
					<colspec colname='c1' />
					<colspec colname='c2' />
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>Element Name</entry>
							<entry>
								Relationship to other Elements
							</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry>Premises</entry>
							<entry>
								There is one premises element in a Tracker document. It is consider the root of the 
								Premises document.  All other elements are children elements of the Premises element.
								The Premises Editor tab 'Premises' provides a form for editing the attributes of the 
								Premise element.
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Location</entry>
							<entry>
								A premises can have an optional Location element to specify address and geolocation details. 
								The Premises Editor tab 'Location' provides a form for editing the attributes of the 'Location'
								element.
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Area</entry>
							<entry>
								A 'Locaton' element can have zero or more optional 'Area' elements to specify sublocation boundries.
								Areas specify locations within the Premises. Specifying areas in a premises allow animals with
								'Sighting' and 'Position' events to be located and traced as they move within the premises. 
								The Premises Editor tab 'Areas' provides a form for creating and editing the attributes of 
								one or more 'Area' elements.
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Animal</entry>
							<entry>
								A premises can have zero or many animals.
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Tag (assigned)</entry>
							<entry>
								An Animal can have one or many tags.
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Tag (unassigned)</entry>
							<entry>A Premises can have zero or many tags that are unassigned.</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Event</entry>
							<entry>
								A Tag can have one or many events.
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Policy (not shown)</entry>
							<entry>
								A Premises can have zero or one Policy for restricting the premises to specific animal
								species and event types. The Premises Editor tab 'Policy' provides a form for creating
							    and editing the attributes of the 'Policy' element. 
							</entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</table>

		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="premisesDataModel_corePremisesAnimals">
	<?dbhtml filename="model/premisesEditorModel_dataModel_animals.html" ?>
	<title>Data Model Animal Elements</title>
	<para>The Premises Data Model supports multiple Animal types as shown in 
		<xref linkend="fig_coreDataModelAnimals" />
				
	   </para>
	   <figure id="fig_coreDataModelAnimals">
		<title>Premises Data Model Animal Elements</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/model/dataModelAnimals.png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	</section>
	
	<section id="premisesDataModel_corePremisesEvents">
	<?dbhtml filename="model/premisesEditorModel_dataModel_events.html" ?>
	<title>Data Model Event Elements</title>
	<para>The Premises Data Model supports multiple Event types as shown in 
	 <xref linkend="fig_coreDataModelEvents1" /> and <xref linkend="fig_coreDataModelEvents2" />.	
	</para>
	 <figure id="fig_coreDataModelEvents1">
		<title>Premises Data Model Event Elements (part 1)</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/model/dataModelEvents1.png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	
	 <figure id="fig_coreDataModelEvents2">
		<title>Premises Data Model Event Elements (part 2)</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/model/dataModelEvents2.png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	 </figure>
	</section>
	
	</section>
	
	<section id="genericEvents">
	<?dbhtml filename="genericEvents/genericEvents.html" ?>
		<title>Custom Events</title>
		<para>The Premises Editor ships with predefined event types that are suitable for documenting most livestock histories. 
		If the predifined event types are not sufficient, the Premises Editor utilizes the <emphasis>Metatype Editor Feature</emphasis>
		and the Metatype documents it creates to define custom event types.
		</para>
		
		
	<section id="genericEvents_creatingCustomEvents"> 
	<?dbhtml filename="genericEvents/genericEvents_creatingCustomEvents.html" ?>
		<title>Creating Custom Events</title>
		
		<para>To define one or more custom events: 
		<itemizedlist>
		<listitem><para>
		Create a Metatype document using the <code>New Metatype Document Wizard</code>
		</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>
		For every custom event define an <emphasis>Object Class Definition</emphasis>, <code>OCD</code>  element; 
		and in the <emphasis>Properties view</emphasis> specify it's properties as:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>Description</code> - an optional description of the custom event
				</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>ID</code> - a unique string identifying the event within the document 
				</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>Name</code> - a user recognizable name for the event
				</para></listitem>
				
			</itemizedlist>
		</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>
		Within each <code>OCD</code> create one or more child <emphasis>Attribute Definition</emphasis>, <code>AD</code> 
		elements to define the attributes of the custom event. These attributes will be displayed in the editor as properties 
		of the event.
		</para></listitem>
		<listitem><para>
		Within each <code>AD</code> child element specify the properties:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>Cardinality</code>, an optional property that specifies the number of values contained in this attribute.
					 The default is <code>0</code>.
				</para></listitem>
				<listitem>
				    <para>
					<code>Data Type</code>, a required property that specifies what type of property value is valid for
					the attribute.  A pull down list will show the options: <code>String</code>, <code>Long</code>,
					<code>Integer</code>, <code>Short</code>, <code>Char</code>, 
					<code>Byte</code>, <code>Double</code>, <code>Float</code> and <code>Boolean</code>
				    </para>
				    <para>When working with custom events in premises documents only values appropriate to the specified data type
				    will be considered valid.  For example a custom event with a data type of <code>Boolean</code> will 
				    only accept <emphasis>true</emphasis> and <emphasis>false</emphasis> as valid values.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>Default</code>, is the default value for this attribute. This default value(s) must be appropriate for  
					the cardinality and data type defined above.
				</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>Description</code>, an optional description of the attribute.  This will be shown in the message panel when
					the user interface is focused on this attribute. 
				</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>ID</code>, document wide identification string for this attribute.
				</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>Max</code>, maximuim value for this attribute.
				</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>Min</code>, minimum value for this attribute.
				</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>Name</code>, user recognizable name for this attribute.
				</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>
					<code>Required</code>, whether this attribute must be given a value by the user for the event to be considered valid.
				</para></listitem>
				
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem><para>
		Within each <code>OCD</code> optionally create a child <code>Icon</code> 
		element to associate an image with the event.
		</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		
		<para>See <xref linkend="fig_genericEvents_create"/> for an screen shot showing a Metatype document that 
		defines two custom events.</para>
		
		<figure id="fig_genericEvents_create">
			<title>Defining Custom Events</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/genericEvents/definingCustomEvents.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
	</section>
		
	<section id="usingCustomEvents">
	<?dbhtml filename="genericEvents/genericEvents_usingCustomEvents.html" ?>
		<title>Using Custom Events in Premises Documents</title>
		<para>
		To use custom events in Premises documents, the Metatype document that defines the custom events must first be loaded 
		as a resource. <footnote><para>This only needs to be done once.  When the premises document is saved and opened again, the Metatype 
		document with the custom event specifications will automatically be associated with the Premises document.</para></footnote>
		To load a resource into a Premises document place the mouse cursor on the root element in the Premises document, right click, 
		and from the pull down menu choose <code>Load Resorce...</code>
		</para>
		
		<figure id="fig_loadMetatypeCustomEventsResource">
			<title>Load Resource Dialog</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/genericEvents/loadResource.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>From the <xref linkend="fig_loadMetatypeCustomEventsResource"/> choose the Metatype document that defines the 
		custom events and press <code>OK</code>.</para>
		
		<para>See <xref linkend="fig_loadedMetatypeCustomEventsResource"/>.</para>
		
		<figure id="fig_loadedMetatypeCustomEventsResource">
			<title>Premises Document Loaded with a Metatype Resource</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/genericEvents/loadedResources.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>When a Premises document is loaded with a Metatype resource, all the custom events from the Metatype document 
		are available for adding to the animal histories of the Premises Document. The Premises Editor user interfaces will also treat
	    the Metatype documents custom events just like predifined events.</para>
	    <para>See <xref linkend="fig_customEventsPickList"/>,
	    <xref linkend="fig_customEventsWizard"/>, and <xref linkend="fig_customEventsView"/>.</para>
		
		<figure id="fig_customEventsPickList">
			<title>Adding an Event in the Premises Editor</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/genericEvents/pickList.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
			
		<figure id="fig_customEventsWizard">
			<title>Adding and Event in the Event View</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/genericEvents/addingAnEventWizard.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
	   </figure>
	   
	   <figure id="fig_customEventsView">
			<title>Modifying Attributes in the Events View</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/genericEvents/eventsView.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
	   </figure>
		
	</section>
	</section>

	<section id="useCase">
      <?dbhtml filename="usecase/premisesEditorModel_useCase.html" ?>
		<title>Premises Editor Use Cases</title>
		<para>
		To best depict what the Premises Editor can do for Tracker users the following 
		section presents a series of <emphasis>Use-Case</emphasis> diagrams.  
		<xref linkend="fig_CoreUseCases" /> shows core usage requirements for the Premises 
		Editor. 
		</para>
		<figure id="fig_CoreUseCases">
			<title>Premises Editor Overview</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/useCases/core.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	
	    <para>
		  Once the Tracker <acronym>BI</acronym> Toolkit and the Premises Editor Feature are installed setup takes less than a minute.
		  Administration use-cases are shown in
		<xref linkend="fig_setUpUseCases" />. 
		</para>
	    
	    <figure id="fig_setUpUseCases">
			<title>Setting Up the Premises Editor</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/useCases/setup.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>
		  Updating document use-cases are shown in
		<xref linkend="fig_updateUseCases" />. 
		</para>
		<figure id="fig_updateUseCases">
			<title>Updating Documents</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/useCases/update.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>
		  Tracker Operators may need to work with large Premises documents. Providing Tracker Operators
		  with the tools to navigate around these large documents has been a major design goal of the 
		  Premises Editor. Navigation use-cases are shown in
		<xref linkend="fig_navigateUseCases" />. 
		</para>
		<figure id="fig_navigateUseCases">
			<title>Navigating in the Editor</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/useCases/navigate.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		
		<para>
		  As shown in previous use-cases Premises Documents can be created and updated by human operators
		  Premises Editor.  To improve efficiency new animals and events can also be added to Premises 
		  Documents by using external tag ID readers connected to the Tracker via data 
		  communications channels.  This is shown in
		<xref linkend="fig_connectedReadersUseCases" />. 
		</para>
		<figure id="fig_connectedReadersUseCases">
			<title>Working with Connected Readers</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/useCases/readers.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
    </section>

</chapter>

