<webpage id="about">
  <config param="rcsdate" value="$Date: 2012-12-12 23:57:38 -0600 (Wed, 12 Dec 2012) $"/>
  <head>
    <title>About</title>
    <summary>
    Information Networking through State of the Art Technology Integration.
    </summary>
    <keywords>Tracker, Business Intelligence, Eclipse, OSGi</keywords>
  </head>
  <para>
	Providing tools, services and 'Business Eco-systems'<footnote><para>An economic community supported by a foundation of 
	interacting organizations and individuals—the organisms of the business world. The economic community produces 
	goods and services of value to customers, who are themselves members of the ecosystem. The member organisms 
	also include suppliers, lead producers, competitors, and other stakeholders. Over time, they coevolve their 
	capabilities and roles, and tend to align themselves with the directions set by one or more central companies. 
	Those companies holding leadership roles may change over time, but the function of ecosystem leader is valued 
	by the community because it enables members to move toward shared visions to align their investments, and to 
	find mutually supportive roles.” - James Moore 1993 Harvard Business Review</para></footnote> that transform livestock 
	commodities into high value food products. 
	</para>
	
  <section id="aboutVerticon">
    <title>Verticon</title>
    <para>
	Verticon develops and integrates software tools, cloud based network services and offers product support and consulting
	services.
	</para>
	
  </section>  

  <section id="valueProp">
    <title>Value Proposition</title>
    <para>
	New state of the art technology trends are changing the face of information management and business to business 
	communication.  
	</para>
	<para>
	These trends can be characterized as the ubiquitous connectivity provided by smart phones, the dynamic 
	infrastructure scaling of cloud computing, the inter-networking of things with RFID, the massive information 
	storage capacity of big data repositories, Online analytical processing (BI) tools, and the Eco-system based 
	development of modular software.
	</para>
	<para> 
	These technologies, when leveraged strategically, provide the means for businesses, and business associations 
	to revolutionize their marketplaces by transforming the management and communication of exchanged information. 
	</para>
	<para>When dynamic bidirectional information networks connect business associates and business processes lead to 
	full utilization of exchanged information; increased market sales, product margin, traceability and product 
	quality result.
	</para>
  </section>  
  
  <section id="mission">
    <title>Mission</title>
    <para>
  	The Verticon Tracker product line leverages state of the art technologies to create tools, networks and Business 
  	Eco-systems that transform livestock commodities into high value recognized products. 
    </para>
    <para>
    	Tracker products offer solutions for Livestock ... 
    
    <itemizedlist mark='opencircle'>
			<listitem>
				<para>Producers;</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem >
				<para>Infrastructure Providers;</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Government Regulators;</para>
			</listitem>
			
	</itemizedlist>
    
    </para>
   </section>

  
</webpage>
