<webpage id="goals">
	<config param="rcsdate"
		value="$Date: 2009-08-18 23:37:34 -0500 (Tue, 18 Aug 2009) $" />
	<head>
		<title>Design Goals</title>
		<summary>
			Methodology, Technology and Direction
    </summary>
		<keywords>Tracker, Business Intelligence, Eclipse, OSGi</keywords>
	</head>

    <section id="frameworkOverview_goals" >
		<title>Project Goals</title>
		<para>
			The Tracker project was undertaken to provide;
			<itemizedlist numeration="opencircle">
				<listitem>
					<para>
						a Business Intelligence Toolkit for the rapid creation of 
						Business Intelligence solutions useful for Livestock
					    producers and infrastructure providers;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						free Open Source technologies to encourage widespread vendor
						integration and user deployment of generic Livestock Business 
						Intelligence solutions;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						lower costing custom solutions for Livestock producers, 
						infrastructure providers and 
						process auditors;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						create ubiquitous livestock event history inter-exchange solutions
						via associations and marketplaces.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
	    <title>Methodology</title>
		<para>
		Utilize state of the art software technologies that leverage component modularization,
	    distributed network computing, and business object modeling. Work within a collaborative 
		business technology friendly environment that adheres to open industry standards, 
		open data interfaces and open source licensing. 
   		</para>
   </section>

	<section id="businessObjects">
		<title>Direction</title>
		<para>The creation of Network Aware Business Objects.</para>
		<para>
			Tracker
			<acronym>BI</acronym>
			Features are network repository resident business objects that
			can be selected by the user for installation in the Tracker Toolkit.
			Once installed Tracker
			<acronym>BI</acronym>
			Features are updated and managed from within the Tracker
			<acronym>BI</acronym>
			Toolkit to meet specific business needs of the user. Tracker
			<acronym>BI</acronym>
			Features support:
			<itemizedlist mark='opencircle'>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open Data formats for improved data management,</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Open Source Code to insure auditing transparency and future
						extensibility,</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Component Based functionality to speed development and
						administration,</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Industry Standardization to meet the needs of a multi-vendor
						integrated marketplace,</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>and Multi-platform runtimes to expand user and use-case
						operating system and hardware platform choices.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>

		</para>
	</section>

</webpage>
