<?xml version='1.0' encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <?dbhtml filename="premisesEditor/premisesEditor.html" ?>
  <title>Agriculture Editor and Location Service</title>
  <section id="overviewAgricultureEditor">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <section id="overviewAgricultureEditorWhatis">
      <title>What is the Agriculture Editor and Location 
      Service?</title>
      <para>The Agriculture Editor and Location Service is a 
      comprehensive open desktop solution for documenting, managing and 
      visualizing geographic livestock herd distributions, individual 
      animal locations, and animal movements within and between 
      premises locations.</para>
      <para>The Agriculture Editor and Location Service is a suite of 
      tools that integrates state of the art Geographic Information 
      System <acronym>GIS</acronym> technologies with Tracker Premises livestock 
      management information.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="overviewAgricultureEditorGoals">
      <title>Project Goals</title>
      <para>As livestock markets continue to adapt to customer requirements,
       more livestock markets will require animal source information to do business. 
       Yet even for producers not facing this requirement, just knowing where animals 
       are located while still on the premises is considered must have requirement.</para>
       <para>Making livestock 
       location information easy to document, lookup and easy to electronically inter-exchange 
       is the primary goal of the Agriculture Editor and Location Service project.</para>
      <para>
        The Agriculture Editor and Location Service provide models, editors and services for the 
        creation and management of documents that:
        <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
          <listitem>
            <para>Reference livestock premises to geographic 
            locations</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Create associated groups of business related 
            livestock premises within geographic regions</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Create named geographical sub-locations within single 
            livestock premises</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate Animals that have moved to geographical 
            sub-locations within a premises</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate Animals that have moved to another premises 
            within associated groups of business related livestock 
            premises</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Assign animal positions based on visual sighting 
            records or data inputs from industry standard GPS 
            devices</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Will serve as the foundation for a full featured distributed livestock Traceability service</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section id="overviewAgricultureFunctinal">
      <title>Functional Overview</title>
      <para>The Agriculture Editor is used to create documents that assign Geographical Locations to Livestock premises.</para>
      <note>
        <para>The Agriculture Editor is dependent on two other Tracker Desktop Features, 
        the Premises Editor and the Geographic Editor. Agriculture documents created by the 
        Agriculture Editor reference elements contained in documents created by these two editors. 
        Geography attributes in the Agriculture documents are references to <code>Container</code> elements 
	     in the *.kml documents created by the Geographic Editor.  Livestock attributes in Agriculture documents
	     are referenced to <code>Premises</code> elements in the *.premises documents created by Premises Editors.</para> 
      </note>
       <para>
      The Location Service provides name and geolocation resolution based on the information contained in 
      specially designated Agriculture documents.  The Location Service enhances all features containing location 
      derived attributes.</para>
      <para>
        The Agriculture Editor and Location Service Feature adds geographical visualization, location resolution 
        and geographic analytical utilities to the Tracker Desktop Business Intelligence Toolkit:
        <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
          <listitem>
            <para>Simple end user visualization of premises geographies 
            through integration with industry standard Geobrowsers.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Geolocation features benefit all types of producers. For those using electronic automation with GPS and RFID 
            readers and those using manual key entry of animal history events</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Desktop editors, views, and utilities for modeling agriculture associations allowing livestock producers 
              auditors, and processors to geographically -
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>manage internal, inter-association and intra-association animal movements and information flows</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>create marketing and/or auditing reports for regional and <emphasis>local</emphasis> based farm 
                  products</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Easily view the location of animals within the local premises.
             <itemizedlist>
             	<listitem>
            		<para>Resolution of locations based on animal Position events that were input from GPS devices associated with RFID readers.
            			Where Position coordinates determine the location names based on best fit (smallest area) of list of 
            			geographically specified locations</para>
          		</listitem>
          		<listitem>
            		<para>Visual sighting of animals with manual assignment of location names selected from list of geographically 
            		specified locations</para>
          		</listitem>
          		<listitem>
            		<para>Most current Sighting event or Position event determines location</para>
            		<para />
          		</listitem>
             </itemizedlist>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Easily view the destination of animals moved to other business partners</para>
          </listitem>
          
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="agricultureEditor_useCase">
  <?dbhtml filename="usecase/agricultureEditor_useCase.html" ?>
    <title>Agriculture Editor Use Cases</title>
    <para>To best depict what the Agriculture Editor can do for Tracker users, the following figure presents a series of 
    <emphasis>Use-Case</emphasis> diagrams. 
    <xref linkend="fig_AgricultureEditorUseCases"/> shows core usage 
    requirements for the Agriculture Editor.</para>
    <figure id="fig_AgricultureEditorUseCases">
      <title>Agriculture Editor Overview</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
       fileref="../images/useCases/editor.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section id="locationService_useCase">
  <?dbhtml filename="usecase/locationService_useCase.html" ?>
    <title>Location Service Use Cases</title>
    <para>The Location Service is not directly accessible to the user, 
    but operates in the background to provide geographical location 
    resolution services to the Premises Editor and Premises document 
    related tools. As a background service it resolves location 
    specific elements and attributes within Premises documents,  
    Premises utilities, and Business Intelligence reporting 
    tools.</para>
    <para>To provide location resolution, the Location Service derives 
    it&apos;s data from one or more of Agriculture documents created by 
    the operator with the Agriculture Editor.</para>
    <para>The Location service provides the following 
    <emphasis>Use-Cases</emphasis> to Tracker users. 
    <xref linkend="fig_LocationServiceUseCases"/> shows core usage 
    requirements for the Location Service.</para>
    <figure id="fig_LocationServiceUseCases">
      <title>Location Service Overview</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
       fileref="../images/useCases/locationService.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  <section id="agricultureDocuments">
   <?dbhtml filename="model/agricultureEditorModel_agricultureDocuments.html" ?>
    <title>Agriculture Documents</title>
    <para>The Agriculture Editor enables users to create, transform and 
    edit documents referencing geographic Locations of Livestock Premises and sub locations 
    within a Premises.</para>
    <note>
    <para>Because Agriculture Documents elements references elements in one or more
    Premises and KML geographic documents, these two document types need to be created 
    before the user creates an Agriculture document.</para>
    </note>
     <para>Agriculture document files utilize a <code>.agri</code> file extension to 
    distinguish them from other types of files.</para>
  </section>
  <section id="agricultureDataModel">
    <?dbhtml filename="model/agricultureEditorModel_agricultureDataModel.html" ?>
    <title>Agriculture Data Model</title>
    <para>Because all user activity centers around the creation and 
    manipulation of <emphasis>Agriculture Documents</emphasis>, 
    understanding the structure (called the <glossterm>data 
    model</glossterm>) of Agriculture documents is the easiest way to 
    learn to use the information management facilities of the Agriculture 
    Editor.</para>
    <section id="agricultureDataModel_coreElements">
      <title>Data Model Core Elements</title>
      <para>All Agriculture documents conform to a very simple structure called the
      <emphasis>Agriculture Data Model</emphasis>. In the Agriculture Data 
      Model, a single Agriculture association is assigned a name and a geographic region.
	  Within this agriculture association there are one or more Location elements. A 
      Location element is a place for assigning livestock premises to geographic locations. 
      The geographic locations assigned to the premises within the Locations may or may not be 
      geographically contained within the Agriculture elements region attribute.</para>
      <para>Core elements of the Agriculture Data Model are shown in 
      <xref linkend="fig_AgricultureDataModel1"/>.</para>
      <figure id="fig_AgricultureDataModel1">
        <title>Agriculture Data Model Elements</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
         fileref="../images/model/agriculture.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
          <listitem>
            <para>The core elements of the Premises Model are depicted 
            as rectangles in the figure.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The notation within the elements are the attributes 
            of the element.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The notation between the elements are the 
            relationships of the elements.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </para>
      <para>
        The following table offers a text explanation of the Element 
        Relationships.
        <table frame="all">
          <title>Core Elements of the Premises Model</title>
          <tgroup align="left" cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
            <colspec colname="c1"/>
            <colspec colname="c2"/>
            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Element Name</entry>
                <entry>Relationship to other Elements</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Agriculture</entry>
                <entry>There is one agriculture in a document</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>association</entry>
                <entry>A Location has a association attribute assigned a name</entry>
              </row>
               <row>
                <entry>geography</entry>
                <entry>Agriculture has a geography attribute assigned to a KML Container element</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>Location</entry>
                <entry>Agriculture can have zero or many locations</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>geography</entry>
                <entry>A Location has a geography attribute assigned to a KML Container element</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>livestock</entry>
                <entry>A Location has a livestock attribute assigned to a Premises element</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section id="editingAgricultureDocuments">
    	<?dbhtml filename="editingAgricultureDocuments/editingAgricultureDocuments.html" ?>
		<title>Editing Agriculture Documents</title>
		<section id="creatingAgricultureDocuments">
			<title>Creating a new Document</title>
			<para>
			To create a new agriculture document. Go to the File menu and launch a 
			<emphasis>New Wizard</emphasis> by selecting the menu items:<code>File|New|Other</code>.
			<xref linkend="fig_createNewAgricultureDocument" />.
			</para>

		<figure id="fig_createNewAgricultureDocument">
			<title>New Wizard for Creating a New Agriculture Document</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/createNewDocument.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>Follow the instructions to choose a project, folder and a name for the document.
		Select Agriculture as the model object and press <code>Finish</code> to create the document. 
			
		</para>
       <figure id="fig_selectAgricultureModelObject">
			<title>New Agriculture Document Wizard Model Object Prompt</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/selectModelObject.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		</section>
		
		<section id="loadingAgricultureDocumentResources">
		<?dbhtml filename="editingAgricultureDocuments/loadingAgricultureDocuments.html" ?>
		<title>Loading Additional Resources into the Document</title>
		 <note>
			<para>
				Since the Agriculture document references Premises document elements and KML document
				elements, one or more of these document resources must already exist in the workspace.
			</para>
		 </note>
			<para>
			To build Location elements in the Agriculture document, the document must first be loaded 
			with the KML and Premsies document resourcess that will be used for the attribute references.
			To load a resource place the mouse cursor on the root element in the document, right click, 
			and from the pull down menu choose <code>Load Resorce...</code>
			</para>
			<figure id="fig_loadAgricultureResource">
			<title>Load Resource Dialog</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/loadResource.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>From the dialog choose the KML or the Premises document that you wish to load. 
			Repeat the loading process to load all the resources that will be referenced by the 
			Agriculture document.</para>
			<figure id="fig_loadedAgricultureResource">
			<title>Agriculture Project with Loaded Resources</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/loadedResources.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</section>
	    
	    <section id="completingAgricultureDocument">
	    <?dbhtml filename="editingAgricultureDocuments/completingAgricultureDocuments.html" ?>
	    <title>Completing an Agriculuture Document</title>
	    <para>When KML documents are loaded as resources into Agriculture documents, the editor choice boxes 
	    associated with the <code>geography</code>
	    attributes of the <code>Agriculture</code> element and the <code>Location</code> elements will be populated
	    by all <code>Container Features</code> elements from all the loaded KML resources. 
	   </para>
	   <figure id="fig_agricultureGeographyPicks">
			<title>Picklist of KML Containers</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/geographyPicks.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			</figure>
	   <para>Likewise, when premises documents are loaded as resources into Agriculture documents, the editor choice 
	    boxes associated with the <code>livestock</code> attribute of the <code>Location</code> element will be 
	    populated by all <code>Premises</code> elements from all the loaded Premises resources.</para>
	    <figure id="fig_completedAgricultureDocument">
			<title>Picklist of Premises</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/completedDocument.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			</figure>
	    </section>

	</section>
	
  <section id="configuringLocationService">
	<?dbhtml filename="locationService/configuringLocationService.html" ?>
	<title>Configuring the Location Service</title>
	
	<section id="requirementsForLocationService">
	 <title>Agriculture Documents as Input to the Location Service</title>
	 <para>The full benefit of declaring premises and geographical locations is achieved when Agriculture 
	documents are defined as input to the Location Service.  
	</para>
	<para>
	In order to assign an agriculture document to the Location Service. The following requirements must be met:
	 <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
          <listitem>
            <para>The agriculture document must be a valid Agriculture documents</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The agriculture document must be named: <code>doc.agri</code></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The agriculture document must be located in the root folder of a project</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The agriculture document must be in a project that has been configured with an <code>Agriculture Nature</code></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
	</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="configuringAgricultureNature">
	<?dbhtml filename="locationService/configuringAgricultureNatures.html" ?>
	<title>Configuring a Project with an Agriculture Nature</title>
	<para>To configure a project with an Agriculture Nature place the mouse cursor on the Project in the 
	<code>Project Explorer</code> right click, and from the pull down menu choose <code>Add/Remove Agriculture Nature</code>.
	</para>
	<figure id="fig_configureAgricultureNature"><!-- 9.10 -->
			<title>Configuring Project with an Agriculture Nature</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/locationService/configuringNature.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<note><para>A project that has been configured as an Agriculture Nature will be designated with a 
	<emphasis>small capital A</emphasis> on the upper right of the project folder icon.</para></note>
	
	</section>
	</section>
	
  <section id="usingLocationService"> 
  <?dbhtml filename="locationService/usingLocationService.html" ?>
  <title>Using the Location Service</title>
   <para>Once a premises has been defined in the <code>doc.agri</code>, placed in the root directory of a
   project, and the project configured with an Agriculture Nature, the Location Service will provide resolution
   services for all of documents in the workspace:</para>
   <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
   		<listitem>
   			<para>Resolving the <code>Premises</code> element's derived <code>address</code> attribute  
   		     to the address in the referenced KML container.</para>
        </listitem>
   		<listitem>
   			<para>Resolving the <code>Animal</code> element's' derived <code>location</code> attribute when
   			the last movement event in the <code>Animal</code> event history is a:</para>
   			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
   				<listitem>
   					<para><code>Position</code> event. Resolution will be the sub location within the 
   					<acronym>KML</acronym> <code>Container</code> that contains the point specified by the
   					 <code>coordinate</code> attribute of the <code>Position</code> event.
   					 See <xref linkend="fig_locationServiceAnimalResolved"/>
   					 </para>
   					  <note><para>If two or more sublocations contain the point, the one with the smallest area
   					  will be choosen.</para></note>
        		</listitem>
   				<listitem>
   					<para><code>MovedOut</code> event. Resolution will be the name of the 
   					<acronym>KML</acronym> <code>Container</code> associated with the <code>Premises uri</code>
   					attribute of the <code>MovedOut</code> event.</para>
   				</listitem>
   			</itemizedlist>
   		</listitem>
   		<listitem>
   			<para>Provide the names of sublocations in a premises so that Premises editors can populate the
   			 pick list of  <code>Sighting location</code> attribute editors</para></listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   <figure id="fig_locationServiceAnimalResolved">
			<title>Example of Resolving an Animal Location from Coordinates</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/locationService/animalPosition.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
   </section>
</chapter>
