<?xml version='1.0' encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <?dbhtml filename="premisesEditor/premisesEditor.html" ?>
  <title>Agriculture Editor and Agriculture Location Service</title>

  <section id="overviewAgricultureEditor">
    <title>Overview</title>

    <section id="overviewAgricultureEditorWhatis">
      <title>What is the Agriculture Editor and Location Service?</title>
      <para>The Agriculture Editor is an editor for specifying business associations of livestock producers and 
      infrastructure providers.
      </para>
      <para>The Agriculture Location Service is a comprehensive desktop based implementation of the Tracker 
      Location Service
      <footnote><para>
      	The Tracker Location Service is a global Tracker application service for resolving the real-world 
      	geographic location of an object.
      	</para>
      	<para>Given the name or identification (ID) of an object, the Location Service can resolve geographic location
      names, addresses, and sub areas of the object. Given the geographic coordinates of an object the service
      can resolve the name of the containing location.
      	</para>
      	<para>The Tracker Location Service aggregates all implementations to provide a single service application 
      	interface to enrich Tracker desktop editors and utilities.
      	</para></footnote>. The Agriculture Location Service implementation utilizes local desktop resident Agriculture 
      	document files to create a geolocation map for resolving geolocation requests.
      </para>
      <para>	
      The Agriculture Editor and Location Service can be used for documenting, resolving and visualizing livestock 
      herd distributions; identifying livestock business associations; and determining individual animal locations, 
      and animal movements within and between premises locations.
      </para>
     
    </section>

    <section id="overviewAgricultureEditorGoals">
      <title>Project Goals</title>
      <para>As livestock markets continue to adapt to customer requirements, more livestock markets will require animal 
      source information and the functionality to do trace-back and trace-forward between business associates. Yet even 
      for some producers not facing this inter-premises requirement, just resolving animal locations, within 
      a premises, is a must have requirement.</para>
       <para>Making livestock location information easy to utilize and easy to electronically inter-exchange while 
       maintaining data privacy within business associations of livestock producers is the goal of the Agriculture 
       Editor and Location Service project.</para>
      <para>
        The Agriculture Editor and Location Service provide models, editors and services for the 
        creation and management of Agriculture documents that:
        <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
          <listitem>
            <para>Specify associated groups of business related livestock premises
            	<footnote>
            	<para>It is the optional 'Location' element and child 'Area' 
            	elements in the Tracker 'Premises' document that specifies the geographic 
            	information that will be used to create the Agriculture Location Service mapping. 
            	</para>
            	</footnote>
            within geographic regions</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Identify agriculture documents that will contribute location data to the Location Service.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate Animals that have moved to geographical  sub-locations within a premises</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate Animals that have moved to another premises 
            within associated groups of business related livestock 
            premises</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Identify a list of sub location areas within  
            premises</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Assign animal positions based on visual sighting 
            records or data inputs from industry standard GPS 
            devices</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Will serve as the foundation for a full featured distributed livestock Traceability service</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>

    <section id="overviewAgricultureFunctinal">
      <title>Functional Overview</title>
      <para>The Agriculture Editor creates documents that assign Livestock premises to Associations.</para>
      <note>
        <para>The Agriculture Editor is dependent on documents created by the Tracker Premises Editor. 
        The Agriculture element <code>Association</code> specifies one or more references to 
        <code>Premises</code> elements in *.premises documents 
        </para> 
      </note>
       <para>
      The Agriculture Location Service provides a geolocation resolution service that is based on the information contained in 
      specially designated Agriculture documents.</para>
      <para>
        The Agriculture Location Service implementation adds geographical visualization, location resolution 
        and geographic analytical utilities to the Tracker Desktop Business Intelligence Toolkit:
        <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
          
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Desktop editors, views, and utilities for modeling agriculture associations allowing livestock producers 
              auditors, and processors to geographically -
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>manage internal, inter-association and intra-association animal movements and information flows</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>create marketing and/or auditing reports for regional and <emphasis>local</emphasis> based farm 
                  products</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Easily view the location of animals within the local premises.
             <itemizedlist>
             	<listitem>
            		<para>Resolution of locations based on animal Position events that were input from GPS devices associated with RFID readers.
            			Where Position coordinates determine the location names based on best fit (smallest area) of list of 
            			geographically specified locations</para>
          		</listitem>
          		<listitem>
            		<para>Visual sighting of animals with manual assignment of location names selected from list of geographically 
            		specified locations</para>
          		</listitem>
          		<listitem>
            		<para>Most current Sighting event or Position event determines location</para>
            		<para />
          		</listitem>
             </itemizedlist>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Easily view the destination of animals moved to other business partners</para>
          </listitem>
         </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section id="agricultureDocuments">
   <?dbhtml filename="model/agricultureEditorModel_agricultureDocuments.html" ?>
    <title>Agriculture Documents</title>
    <para>The Agriculture Editor enables users to create and 
    edit documents that specify associations  Livestock Premises.</para>
    <note>
    <para>Because Agriculture Documents elements references elements in one or more
    Premises, the Premises documents need to be created before the user creates an 
    Agriculture document.</para>
    </note>
     <para>Agriculture document files utilize a <code>.agri</code> file extension to 
    distinguish them from other types of files.</para>
  </section>
  
  <section id="editingAgricultureDocuments">
    	<?dbhtml filename="editingAgricultureDocuments/editingAgricultureDocuments.html" ?>
		<title>Editing Agriculture Documents</title>
		<section id="creatingAgricultureDocuments">
			<title>Creating a new Document</title>
			<para>
			To create a new agriculture document. Go to the File menu and launch a 
			<emphasis>New Wizard</emphasis> by selecting the menu items:<code>File|New|Other</code>.
		
			<figure id="fig_createNewAgricultureDocument">
			<title>New Wizard for Creating a New Agriculture Document</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/createNewDocument.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			</figure>
	     </para>
		<para>Follow the instructions to choose a project, folder and a name for the document.
		Select Association as the model object and press <code>Finish</code> to create the document. 
			
		</para>
       <figure id="fig_selectAgricultureModelObject">
			<title>New Agriculture Document Wizard ()Model Object Prompt</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/selectModelObject.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		</section>
		
		<section id="loadingAgricultureDocumentResources">
		<?dbhtml filename="editingAgricultureDocuments/loadingAgricultureDocuments.html" ?>
		<title>Loading Additional Resources into the Document</title>
		 <note>
			<para>
				Since the Agriculture document references Premises elements, one or 
				more of these Premises documents must exist as resources in the workspace.
			</para>
		 </note>
			<para>
			To enable the Agriculture Editor to create references to Premises the Premises
			documents must be loaded as resources in the Agriculture document.  
			When all the needed Premises documents are loaded as 
			resources to the Agriculture document, these Premises elements 
			can then be referenced as values of the Association Livestock 
			attribute.</para>
			<para>
			To load a resource place the mouse cursor on the root element in the document, right click, 
			and from the pull down menu choose <code>Load Resource...</code>
			</para>
			<figure id="fig_loadAgricultureResource">
			<title>Load Resource Dialog</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/loadResource.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>From the dialog choose the KML or the Premises document that you wish to load. 
			Repeat the loading process to load all the resources that will be referenced by the 
			Agriculture document.</para>
			<figure id="fig_loadedAgricultureResource">
			<title>Agriculture Project with Loaded Resources</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/loadedResources.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</section>
	    
	    <section id="completingAgricultureDocument">
	    <?dbhtml filename="editingAgricultureDocuments/completingAgricultureDocuments.html" ?>
	    <title>Completing an Agriculuture Document</title>
	    
	   <para>When premises documents are loaded as resources into Agriculture documents, the editor  
	    screens associated with the <code>Livestock</code> attribute of the <code>Association</code> element will be 
	    populated by all <code>Premises</code> elements from all the loaded Premises resources.</para>
	    <figure id="fig_completedAgricultureDocument">
			<title>Picklist of Premises</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/completedDocument.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			</figure>
	    </section>

	</section>

  <section id="agricultureDataModel">
    <?dbhtml filename="model/agricultureEditorModel_agricultureDataModel.html" ?>
    <title>Agriculture Data Model</title>
    <para>Because all user activity centers around the creation and manipulation 
    of Agriculture Documents <emphasis>Association</emphasis>, understanding the structure 
    (called the <glossterm>data model</glossterm>) of Agriculture documents is the easiest 
    way to learn to how to create documents with the Agriculture Editor.</para>
    <section id="agricultureDataModel_coreElements">
      <title>Data Model Core Elements</title>
      <para>All Agriculture documents conform to a very simple structure called the
      <emphasis>Agriculture Data Model</emphasis>. In the Agriculture Data 
      Model, there is only a single element called an <emphasis>Association</emphasis>.
	  The Association has three simple text based attributes, <code>name</code>,
	  <code>description</code> and <code>comments</code>;
	  and one complex attribute <code>livestock</code>. The <code>livestock</code> attribute
	  is a multvalue attribute that references one or more Premises elements.</para>
      <para>Core elements of the Agriculture Data Model are shown in 
      <xref linkend="fig_AgricultureDataModel1"/>.</para>
      <figure id="fig_AgricultureDataModel1">
        <title>Agriculture Data Model Elements</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
         fileref="../images/model/agriculture.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
          <listitem>
            <para>The only element of the Agriculture Model, Association is depicted 
            as a rectangle in the figure.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The notation within the Association element are its attributes.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The notation outside of the Association element represents the 
            <code>livestock</code> attribute's references to external Premises document elements.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </para>
      <para>
        The following table offers a text explanation of the Association elements 
        relationships.
        <table frame="all">
          <title>Core Elements of the Agriculture Model</title>
          <tgroup align="left" cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
            <colspec colname="c1"/>
            <colspec colname="c2"/>
            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Element Name</entry>
                <entry>Relationship to other Elements</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Association</entry>
                <entry>This is the only element in a document.</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>name</entry>
                <entry>Asssociation has a name attribute.</entry>
              </row>
               <row>
                <entry>description</entry>
                <entry>Association has a description attribute.</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>livestock</entry>
                <entry>Association has a multivalue livestock attribute.</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>Premises</entry>
                <entry>Multiple Premises elements can be referenced by the livestock attribute.</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>

  <section id="agricultureEditor_useCase">
  <?dbhtml filename="usecase/agricultureEditor_useCase.html" ?>
    <title>Agriculture Editor Use Cases</title>
    <para>To best depict what the Agriculture Editor can do for Tracker users, the following figure presents a series of 
    <emphasis>Use-Case</emphasis> diagrams. 
    <xref linkend="fig_AgricultureEditorUseCases"/> shows core usage 
    requirements for the Agriculture Editor.</para>
    <figure id="fig_AgricultureEditorUseCases">
      <title>Agriculture Editor Overview</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
       fileref="../images/useCases/editor.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>

  <section id="locationService_useCase">
  <?dbhtml filename="usecase/locationService_useCase.html" ?>
    <title>Location Service Use Cases</title>
    <para>The Location Service is not directly accessible to the user, 
    but operates in the background to provide geographical location 
    resolution services to the Premises Editor and Premises document 
    related tools. As a background service it resolves location 
    specific elements and attributes within Premises documents,  
    Premises utilities, and Business Intelligence reporting 
    tools.</para>
    <para>To provide location resolution, the Location Service derives 
    it&apos;s data from one or more of Agriculture documents created by 
    the operator with the Agriculture Editor.</para>
    <para>The Location service provides the following 
    <emphasis>Use-Cases</emphasis> to Tracker users. 
    <xref linkend="fig_LocationServiceUseCases"/> shows core usage 
    requirements for the Location Service.</para>
    <figure id="fig_LocationServiceUseCases">
      <title>Location Service Overview</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
       fileref="../images/useCases/locationService.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>

  <section id="configuringLocationService">
	<?dbhtml filename="locationService/configuringLocationService.html" ?>
	<title>Configuring the Location Service</title>
	
	<section id="requirementsForLocationService">
	 <title>Agriculture Documents as Input to the Location Service</title>
	 <para>The full benefit of declaring premises and geographical locations is achieved when Agriculture 
	documents are defined as input to the Location Service.  
	</para>
	<para>
	In order to assign an agriculture document to the Location Service. The following requirements must be met:
	 <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
          <listitem>
            <para>The agriculture document must be a valid Agriculture documents</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The agriculture document must be named: <code>doc.agri</code></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The agriculture document must be located in the root folder of a project</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The agriculture document must be in a project that has been configured with an <code>Agriculture Nature</code></para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
	</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="configuringAgricultureNature">
	<?dbhtml filename="locationService/configuringAgricultureNatures.html" ?>
	<title>Configuring a Project with an Agriculture Nature</title>
	<para>To configure a project with an Agriculture Nature place the mouse cursor on the Project in the 
	<code>Project Explorer</code> right click, and from the pull down menu choose <code>Add/Remove Agriculture Nature</code>.
	</para>
	<figure id="fig_configureAgricultureNature"><!-- 9.10 -->
			<title>Configuring Project with an Agriculture Nature</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/locationService/configuringNature.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<note><para>A project that has been configured as an Agriculture Nature will be designated with a 
	<emphasis>small capital A</emphasis> on the upper right of the project folder icon.</para></note>
	
	</section>
	</section>
	
  <section id="usingLocationService"> 
  <?dbhtml filename="locationService/usingLocationService.html" ?>
  <title>Using the Location Service</title>
   <para>Once a premises has been defined in the <code>doc.agri</code>, placed in the root directory of a
   project, and the project configured with an Agriculture Nature, the Location Service will provide resolution
   services for all of Premises documents in the workspace:</para>
   <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
   		<listitem>
   			<para>Resolving the <code>Premises</code> element's derived <code>address</code> attribute  
   		     to the address in the referenced Premises Location element.</para>
        </listitem>
   		<listitem>
   			<para>Resolving the <code>Animal</code> element's' derived <code>location</code> attribute when
   			the last movement event in the <code>Animal</code> event history is a:</para>
   			<itemizedlist mark="bullet">
   				<listitem>
   					<para><code>Position</code> event. Resolution will be the sub location within the 
   					 <code>Location Area</code> boundaries that contains the point specified by the
   					 <code>coordinate</code> attribute of the <code>Position</code> event.
   					 See <xref linkend="fig_locationServiceAnimalResolved"/>
   					 </para>
   					  <note><para>If two or more sublocations contain the point, the one with the smallest area
   					  will be choosen.</para></note>
        		</listitem>
   				<listitem>
   					<para><code>MovedOut</code> event. Resolution will be the name of the 
   					<code>Location</code> associated with the <code>Premises uri</code>
   					attribute of the <code>MovedOut</code> event.</para>
   				</listitem>
   			</itemizedlist>
   		</listitem>
   		<listitem>
   			<para>Provide the names of sublocations in a premises so that Premises editors can populate the
   			 pick list of  <code>Sighting location</code> attribute editors</para></listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   <figure id="fig_locationServiceAnimalResolved">
			<title>Example of Resolving an Animal Location from Coordinates</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/locationService/animalPosition.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
   </section>
</chapter>
