<?xml version='1.0' ?><!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
	<title>about</title>
	<chapter id="TrackerMongoStore">
		<title>Tracker Mongo Store</title>
		<para>com.verticon.tracker.store.mongo Version 0.1.0</para>
		
		<section id="Introduction">
			<title>Introduction</title>
			<para>Tracker Mongo Store is a multi-user enterprise class solution for storage and retrieval of Livestock Business Intelligence documents. </para>
		</section>
		<section id="UsersofTrackerDesktop">
			<title>Users of Tracker Desktop</title>
			<para>Authorized users of the Tracker Desktop can archive Premises animal life data and event histories to a MongoDB data store. Authorized users can also retrieve information about  </para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>a single animal and its</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>event history </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>route between premises locations</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>all the animals in a premises within a specified time frame</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>event histories of all animals</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/Premises_Desktop.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
			<section id="DesktopSupportRequirements">
				<title>Desktop Support Requirements</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Administration </para>
						<orderedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>User designated as an Administrator</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>Manages access rules for all other users</para>
								<orderedlist>
									<listitem>
										<para>Access rules are document based and are loaded by the administrator into MongoDB</para>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para>Users are identified by the user name and the machine name they are logged into</para>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para>Users are authorized to publish animal event histories from one or more premises</para>
									</listitem>
									<listitem>
										<para>Users must be authorized by the administrator to read animal event histories from other premises than their own</para>
									</listitem>
								</orderedlist>
							</listitem>
						</orderedlist>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tracker Desktop archival of Agriculture GeoLocations, Premises and Animals</para>
						<orderedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>Archival support for one or multiple Premises</para>
							</listitem>
						</orderedlist>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Tracker Desktop retrieval </para>
						<orderedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>All animals in a Premises</para>
								<orderedlist>
									<listitem>
										<para>Given a date range and premises uri a retrieval request will generate Tracker premises documents containing animals that were resident during the given date range</para>
									</listitem>
								</orderedlist>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>Single animal</para>
								<orderedlist>
									<listitem>
										<para>Given an animal id, creates KML documents for individual animals showing Geo location routing between Premises locations</para>
									</listitem>
								</orderedlist>
							</listitem>
						</orderedlist>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Eclipse BIRT will support the reporting of geo locations, animal histories and movements </para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="iRouterSupport">
			<title>iRouter Support</title>
			<para>iRouter sensor and actuator networks can now use MongoDB for real time transaction recording of any Tracker Premises events.  </para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/Premises_iRouter.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
			<section id="iRouterComponentRequirements">
				<title>iRouter Component Requirements</title>
				<orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Animal Tag recording to MongoDB</para>
						<orderedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>Tags can contain one or more events</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>Runs in iRouter appliances for headless applications for automatic recording of tag events from one or more fixed sensors</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>Runs in Tracker Desktop BI Toolkit for hands free saving of animals, tags and events originating in iRouter sensor networks</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>Multiple components instances can be configured to connect to one or more MongoDB stores</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>Supports event updates to existing animals and the runtime creation of new animals</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>iRouter Consumer component that leverages the power of the iRouter infrastructure for creating complex sensor and actuator based solutions.</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>Configurable instances can support one or more tag readers or virtual tag producers</para>
							</listitem>
						</orderedlist>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section id="Implementation">
			<title>Implementation</title>
			<para>An OSGi Declarative Services Factory component which implements an iRouter (Tag) Consumer and a com.verticon.tracker.store.ITrackerStore.</para>
		</section>
		<section id="iRouterExample">
			<title>iRouter Example</title>
			<para>Goal: Demonstrate an iRouter component configuration that highlights the functionality of the Tracker Mongo Store</para>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Components used</para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>TruTest Proxy </para>
							<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para>This will serve at the top of the event production chain to produce events associated with a TruTest scale head indicator</para>
									<itemizedlist>
										<listitem>
											<para>The scale will produce events as the weights of the animals are changed, these weight measurements will be sent in the 
												<emphasis>raw.animal.weight</emphasis> scope
											</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para>When an animal EID is detected on the scale head that eid will be produced in the 
												<emphasis>animal.eid</emphasis> scope
											</para>
										</listitem>
										<listitem>
											<para>When the operator presses the Enter Button that event will be produced in the 
												<emphasis>transaction.state</emphasis> scope  
											</para>
										</listitem>
									</itemizedlist>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Premises Event Producer</para>
							<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para>This component will consume all products sent by the TruTest Proxy and on the detection of a 
										<emphasis>transaction.state</emphasis> indicating that the operator pressed the Enter Button, this component will produce the last measurement received and identify it with the animal eid.
									</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Premises Animal Producer</para>
							<itemizedlist>
								<listitem>
									<para>This component also sits towards the top of the event production chain, but consumes Animal EIDs on the 
										<emphasis>animal.eid</emphasis> scope and Enter Button presses on the 
										<emphasis>transaction.state</emphasis> scope that have originated on the TruTest Proxy.  Associated with this component is a 
										<emphasis>URI</emphasis> referencing an Tracker Premises Animal template in an external document. Production cycle of this component starts when a Enter Button press is detected. Then the Animal Template is copied, given the EID from the TruTest, and sent to consumers.
									</para>
								</listitem>
							</itemizedlist>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Tracker Mongo Store consumes products from the Premises Event Producer and the Premises Animal Producer and creates these on the MongoDB. </para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Startup and Configuration</para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>MongoDB must be installed and running on the local host</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Startup Tracker</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>From the 
								<emphasis>Configuration</emphasis> menu, invoke 
								<emphasis>Import iRouter Configuration</emphasis>
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Import that configuration 
								<emphasis>autotype.metatype</emphasis> document in this project
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>TruTest simulator</para>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>Download and install the Tracker simulator product </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>In the installation directory run the simulator executable</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>In a web browser go to 
								<ulink url="http://localhost:8081/client/devices">Simulated Devices</ulink> and start the TruTest simulator
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Select a TruTest simulator </para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>When the TruTest simulator comes up the 
								<emphasis>Connection</emphasis> should be Y
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>Change the EID, the weight and press the record button to simulate a transaction</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<section id="iRouterMonitorViewoftheDemonstration">
				
					<title>iRouter Monitor View of the Demonstration</title>
					<para>In the iRouter Monitor View you should see the components displayed something like:</para>
					<para>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/irouterMonitor.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</para>
				
			</section>
		</section>
		
	</chapter>
</book>