<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DockBook XML V4.5//EN" 
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" >
<chapter id="chReader">
     <?dbhtml filename="reader/reader.html" ?>
	<title>Tag ID Reader</title>
     <section>
	<?dbhtml filename="overview/readerOverview.html" ?>
	<title>Tag ID Reader Overview</title>
	<section>
		<title>Adding Event Transactions to Documents</title>
		<para>
			Tracker provides two types of editors for working with Premises documents. For 
			electronic input of data via connections to Tag Readers a Transaction editor is used.
			The Premises Transaction editor can connect to one or more <acronym>RFID</acronym> 
			Tag Readers.  As animal tags are read by connected Tag readers the tag ids will be added by
			Transaction editors to the document as aniaml history events for the animal identified by the 
			tag ID.
			<note>
				<para>
					Tracker does not require the use of <acronym>RFID</acronym> Tag Readers or special tag ID
					types to create and or manage animal history events. History events can easily be added 
					manually or imported from other files.  If no electronic reading of tags is required just 
					use the non-transaction based Premises Editor. 
				</para>
			</note>
		</para>
		<para>
			Similar to Tracker Bulk Event Processing, Tracker Readers use Animal Document Templates to
			<emphasis>associate</emphasis> event histories with specific <acronym>RFID</acronym> reader 
			tag IDs. As <acronym>RFID</acronym> reader tag IDs are received they are published as one
			or more history events of the Animal corresponding to the Tag/@idNumber.
		</para>
		<para>
			Currently there are four types of connections to Readers supported by the Tracker.
			<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
        		<listitem>
        		<para>Bluetooth Reader - connects to Bluetooth RFID tag readers;</para>
        		</listitem>
       			 <listitem>
        		<para>Serial Port Reader - connects to Serial Port RFID tag readers;</para>
        		</listitem>
        		<listitem>
        		<para>Generating Reader - generates random test tags from a file. (For testing only);</para>
        		</listitem>
       			 <listitem>
        		<para>File Reader - reads Tag/@idNumbers as they are appended to a capture file.</para>
        		</listitem>
            </orderedlist>
		</para>

	</section>

	<section>
		<?dbhtml filename="overview/readerOverview_fileTailing.html" ?>
		<title>File Reader</title>
		<para>
			In most cases Readers will use Bluetooth or Serial Port connections. But in cases where non-standard
			reader connections or audit records are required a File Reader can be used.
		</para>
		<para>
			Tag readers transmit the numbers representing the animal id as an <acronym>ASCII</acronym> 
			text message. A generic way to handle connections to RFID devices is to use a terminal emulator
			program to connect the Tag reader and capture output from the connection to a file. As tags are 
			read by the reader the tag IDs will be appended to the end of the file.
		</para>
		<para>
			Tracker's File Reader can be configured to periodically read tag IDs added to the tail end of a
			specified text file.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Usage and operations</title>
		<section>
			<?dbhtml filename="overview/readerOverview_usageAndOperations.html" ?>
			<title>Tracker Reader View</title>
			<para>
				To show the Readers View. From the Workbench <code>Window</code> menu
				<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select <code>Show View</code>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select <code>Other</code>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select <code>Tracker</code>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select <code>Readers</code>
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para>
			<para>
				Typical premises projects contain a premises document and one or more animal template documents. 
				To begin, make sure your project contains one or more animal template documents. Next open the premises
				document with the Premises Transaction editor.  This document and Transaction Editor are now set
				as the active editor and active document. In the Readers view invoke the <emphasis>Add Readers Wizard</emphasis>
				by selecting the plus symbol in the view toolbar.  A list of all the animal templates in your active project
				will be shown.  Pick one and continue to follow the prompts in the wizard to add the kind of reader you require.
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<?dbhtml filename="overview/readerOverview_configuringFileTailing.html" ?>
			<title>Global Configuration of File Reader Timers</title>
			<para>
				To change the timing of parameters of all the configured File Readers. 
				From the Workbench <code>Window</code> menu: 
				<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select <code>Preferences...</code>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select <code>Tracker</code>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select <code>FileReader</code>
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para>
			<para>
				Configuring requires setting the preferences for: 
			</para>
			<para>
				The <code>Capture File Read Interval</code> is the time interval
				to wait before rereading the file for new messages.
			</para>
			
		</section>
	</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
