<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- 
<!DOCTYPE webpage PUBLIC "-//SF DocBook//DTD Website V2.0//EN"
          SYSTEM "http://www.sf.net/docbook/release/website/2.0/website.dtd>
 -->

<webpage id="home">
	<config param="rcsdate" value="$Date$" />
	<head>
		<title>Tracker</title>
		<summary>Business Intelligence, mobile and big data solutions for Livestock Agriculture Professionals</summary>
		<keywords>Livestock, Open Source, NAIS, XML, Eclipse, RFID,
			Herd management
		</keywords>
	</head>
	<section id="tracker">
		<title>Tracker Full-Spectrum Solution for Animal Agriculture</title>
	<para>
	Verticon’s Tracker is a full-spectrum solution of <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Business_intelligence">business intelligence</ulink> products and services 
	that offers a more efficient way for animal husbandry, livestock producers, infrastructure providers 
	and market regulators to manage, integrate and network multi-species animal life data, animal movements, 
	animal event history, Electronic Certificate of Veterinarian Inspections (eCVI), and  premises information. 
	</para>
	<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Manage</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					    Tracker <olink targetdoc="trackerPro">
						Workbench</olink> is a desktop solution that provides project management tools, editors and business 
					    intelligence utilities for documenting, managing, analyzing and reporting livestock and premises information.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Integrate</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Tracker <olink targetdoc="iRouter">
						<acronym>iRouter</acronym></olink> reduces complexity by “integrating” sensors, actuators, and RFID readers creating a non-intrusive, 
						easily deployed, adaptive solution for building the Agri-premises based Internet of Things (IoT) . 
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Network</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Tracker <olink targetdoc="trackerCloud">
						Cloud</olink> offers dynamic B2B bidirectional exchange of product value information enabling 
						the creation of Agri-Business Ecosystems which lead to increased market sales, higher product margins, 
						better traceability and inventory control, and improved product quality.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
		</variablelist>
	<para>
			Tracker as Open source free software built on the Open System standards <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/">Eclipse</ulink>
			and <ulink url="http://www.osgi.org/">OSGi</ulink> allows thousands of off the shelf solutions to be 
			added and customization to be easily achieved by adding new industry standard components.  Tracker runs on 
			multiple platforms and operating systems, including  desktops, laptops, appliances and servers.  
	</para>
	<para>
	Serving government agencies, resellers, animal producers, infrastructure providers, managers, processors, and certification 
	agencies, Tracker also offers a low cost entry to small farmers to document best practices  to certify product value.
	</para>
	</section>
	<section id="keyfeatures">
		<title>Key Benefits</title>
		<para>
		Tracker provides the tools needed by Professional Livestock Producers, Processors, and
		Process Auditors who wish to:
		</para>

		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Document Livestock Herds and Premises</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					    Tracker provides the easiest way to document all the Livestock herds within a 
					    Premises. By turning manual and/or electronic input of Livestock event data 
					    into small, portable documents based on an Open Industry standards
					    based format.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Manage Online and Offline Data</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Tracker provides utilities for on-line operations and off-line 
						(back room) data navigation, movement, and transformation of Livestock 
						Event and related data.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Easily access information</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<olink targetdoc="trackerLite">Tracker Lite</olink>
						is an easy to use smartphone application that gives users 
						access to networked premises information and allows them to acquire new animal 
						information. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Manage Physical Sensors and Actuators</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Tracker <olink targetdoc="iRouter">iRouter appliance
						<acronym>iRouter</acronym></olink>
						is a generic data integration framework to 
						acquire, transform and exchange data between network connected sensors and 
						actuators. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Analyze Trends</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Tracker data models are based on  
						<ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eclipse_Modeling_Framework">
						<acronym>EMF</acronym></ulink>
						the industry standard Eclipse Modeling Framework
						, <ulink url="http://www.osgi.org/About/Technology?section=2">
						<acronym>OSGi</acronym></ulink>
						the Open Systems Gateway Initiative
						plug-in component extension framework, to allow for easy interfacing
					    with existing Eclipse Analytical Features, as well as custom, and third party
					    business analysis tools. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Create Reports</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Tracker Reporting utilizes the
						<ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/birt/intro/"><acronym>BIRT</acronym></ulink>
						open source reporting system for the design and display of compelling Livestock
						Information Reports.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Collaborate with Associates</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						 Tracker creates small portable documents based on an Open
						<acronym>XML</acronym> standards based format. The size and format of these
					     documents make them perfect for sharing via email, removable media, and web based
					     data inter-exchanges.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Register, Archive and Trace Locations</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						 Tracker cloud services offers a highly scalable, reliable way to register premises information,
						 archive animal life data and event history and do animal traceback and traceforward 
						 queries.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			
		</variablelist>
		
	</section>
	
	<section id="whatsnew">
		<title>What's New?</title>
		<para>
		See the latest status of the project at the
			<ulink url="http://tracker-project.verticon.com/verticon_Tracker">
				Tracker Project Management Website.</ulink>
		</para>
	</section>
</webpage>
