<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
 "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  	<?dbhtml filename="editors/editors.html" ?>
	<title>Provisioned Editors</title>
	<para>Livestock producers, processors and auditors require tools for
	modeling, recording, editing, and reporting on livestock operational information. These tools
	must be able to meet requirements common to each type of livestock operation but also be capable of adapting to 
	specific use cases. For each use case the essential consideration is how to structure 
	or <emphasis>model</emphasis> the operational data to ensure vital information can be 
	efficiently captured, stored, analyzed, and utilized in a operationally valuable way.
	</para>
	
	<para>Common operational use cases are analyzed, then modeled by Tracker business analysts resulting
	in concise <emphasis>data model</emphasis> specifications.  From these data model specifications 
	Tracker engineers craft use case specific editors, tools, and utilities which are then
    delivered as Tracker features to end users.
	</para>
	
	<para>The Tracker product line
	consists of the following data model specific Editor Features:
	<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
				<listitem>
					<para>Premises Editor;<footnote>
						<para>Premises Editor is the primary Tracker Livestock editor and its associated data model 
						is often extended by the other data model editors.</para>
						</footnote>
				  </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Fair Editor;<footnote>
						<para>Extends the Premises Editor to model and document people and animals at a 
						Livestock Exhibition. The Premises Editor and the Fair Editor are the initial Tracker editors.</para>
						</footnote>
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Abattoir Premises Editor;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Auction Premises Editor;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Livestock Transportation Editor;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Custom Editors.<footnote>
						<para>Custom editors are based on a individual operational use case analysis and resulting data model.</para>
						</footnote>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
 		</para>

</chapter>
	
