<webpage id="products">
  <config param="rcsdate" value="$Date: 2009-08-19 20:26:08 -0500 (Wed, 19 Aug 2009) $"/>
  <head>
    <title>Products</title>
    <summary>
    Tools for livestock information management professionals.
    </summary>
    <keywords>Livestock, Tracker, Business Intelligence, Eclipse, OSGi, Smartphone, MongoDB, Cloud, Android</keywords>
  </head>
  <para>
    The Tracker products are a suite of information management tools and network service solutions for 
    <emphasis>Animal Agriculture producers</emphasis>, 
  	<emphasis>Infrastructure providers</emphasis> and <emphasis>Process control auditors</emphasis>. 
 	<itemizedlist mark='opencircle'>
			<listitem>
				<para>Desktop and Laptop based Project management workbench and Business Intelligence toolkit;</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem >
				<para>Machine to Machine (M2M) infrastructure for integrating data, sensors, systems and machines to create
				Agriculture Premises Internet of Things (Iot);</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Business to Business (B2B) network service for communicating market inventory, transactions and events 
				between livestock business associates;</para>
			</listitem>
			
	</itemizedlist>
    </para>
 
  <section id="productLine">
    <title>Tracker Product Line</title>
    <para>
  	Tracker Products:
 	<itemizedlist mark='opencircle'>
			<listitem>
				<para><olink targetdoc="trackerPro">Tracker Workbench</olink> is a project management workbench and 
				business intelligence toolkit for premises and livestock Data Acquisition, Analysis, Reporting and 
				Integration;</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><olink targetdoc="iRouter">iRouter</olink> is a configurable network event processor and M2M infrastructure for 
				the integration of sensors and actuators and the building of Premises based Internet of Things (IoT).</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><olink targetdoc="trackerCloud">Tracker Cloud</olink> is a B2B network collaboration service for notification,
				archival, retrieval and query of premises, livestock, and certificate of veterinarian inspections;</para>
			</listitem>
			
			<listitem >
				<para><olink targetdoc="trackerLite">Tracker Lite</olink> is an easy to use smart phone application for
				acquisition and retrieval of Livestock premises and animal information;</para>
			</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
    </para>
    </section>

  
  
</webpage>
