<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DockBook XML V4.5//EN" 
			"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">

<chapter id="DesktopProduct">
    <?dbhtml filename="desktopProduct/desktopProduct.html" ?>
	<title>Tracker Desktop BI Toolkit</title>
	
    <section id="Overview">
	<title>Overview</title>
	
	<section>
	<title>What is the Tracker Desktop BI Toolkit?</title>

	<para>
		The Tracker Desktop BI Toolkit is a desktop based Business Intelligence 
		(<acronym>BI</acronym>) solutions toolkit for animal agriculture professionals. 
		The Tracker Desktop Toolkit is a <emphasis>network aware rich client platform</emphasis>
		that can be installed with one or more user selected <acronym>BI</acronym> features.
	</para>
	<para>
		Tracker Desktop Toolkit is based on the Eclipse Rich Client Platform (RCP), the Eclipse
		Modeling Framework (EMF) and Open System Gateway Initiative (OSGi) technologies.
	</para>
     </section>
     
     <section><title>Getting Started</title>
     <para>Go to the Tracker website <ulink url="http://tracker.verticon.com/downloads/index.html">
						<citetitle>Tracker Website</citetitle></ulink>
						and follow the installation instructions. </para>
     <para>Once the Tracker BI Toolkit product is installed users can easily add tools 
	to meet their unique information management requirements.  Tracker BI Toolkit can be extended with one or more optional features:
	<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
				<listitem>
					<para>features that contain editors for creating and managing business specific information;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>features that contain task specific utilities and tools for complimenting information;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>features that contain business intelligence reporting tools for presenting and analyzing information;</para>
				</listitem>
				
			</itemizedlist>
 		</para>
 		
 		<para>To add tools, go to the <emphasis>Help</emphasis> menu and select <emphasis>Install New Software</emphasis>, 
 		From the Install Wizard, in the <emphasis>Work with</emphasis> selection box, select the entry 
 		<emphasis>Tracker Release - http://tracker.verticon.com/Tracker/updates</emphasis>.
 		
 		</para>
 		<figure id="fig_ProductFeatures">
      		<title>Tracker BI Toolkit Product Features</title>
      		<mediaobject>
      			<imageobject><imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/gettingStarted/AvailableSoftware.png"/></imageobject>
      		</mediaobject>
    	</figure>
     <note><para>You can also use a cheat sheet to assist with adding features. Go to the <emphasis>Help</emphasis> menu
 		and selecting Cheat Sheets.  From the <emphasis>Tracker</emphasis> entry select <emphasis>Adding Tracker Features to the Tracker Desktop Toolki6t</emphasis>. </para></note>
     </section>
  
	<section id="desktopDefinitions">
	<?dbhtml filename="overview/desktopOverview_definitions.html" ?>
	<title>Workbench Instances, Workspaces, and Projects</title>
		<para>The main focus of activity in the Tracker Application is the editing of Animal Premises Documents.  In order to discuss the mechanics of editing Tracker Animal Premises Documents, some definitions are in order:
		<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
			    <listitem>
					<para>A Tracker Desktop Toolkit <emphasis>installation</emphasis>  is a location on your disk 
					that contains a distribution of the Tracker. When you unpack a Tracker distribution 
					to a location on your disk, you effectively create a local platform installation at 
					that location. The installation contains a set of tools that were packaged together 
					by the organization that created the distribution. Each of the tools in the platform 
					installation contributes some functionality to the Tracker. You may have several 
					platform installations on your machine, each of which may contain a different set of 
					tools. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>A Tracker<emphasis>workbench instance</emphasis> is a runtime instance of the 
					Tracker. Every time you launch the Tracker, a workbench instance is created, making 
					the tools in the platform installation from which the instance was loaded available 
					for use.  
					</para>
					<para> For more information, see the Workbook User Guide concept definition for
						<ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/concepts-2.htm"><citetitle>Workbench</citetitle></ulink>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>A Tracker <emphasis>workspace</emphasis> is a location on your disk that is 
					associated with a running workbench instance. It contains the resources (Tracker 
					Documents, files, folders, etc.) that comprise the <emphasis>projects</emphasis> you 
					work on. The tools contained in the platform installation from which the workbench 
					instance was launched can be used to work with the projects in the workspace. Each 
					workbench instance has exclusive access to its associated workspace: concurrently 
					running workbench instances can not share the same workspace. </para>
				</listitem>
				
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		
	</section>
	<section id="Perspective">
	    <?dbhtml filename="overview/desktopOverview_perspective.html" ?>
		<title>Perspective, Editors and Views</title>
		
		<para>Within the Tracker Workbench, Documents are edited, manipulated, and examined with 
		data model specific Document Editors and Views.  To assist you as you work with Documents, 
		a Tracker <emphasis>Perspective</emphasis> visualizes and positions these Tracker specific 
		Editors and Views within the Workbench as shown in <xref 
		linkend="fig_fullScreenShot"/>.
       </para>
       <figure id="fig_fullScreenShot">
                <title>Tracker Perspective
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/overview/fullScreenShot.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
        </figure>
		<para> For more information, see the Workbook User Guide concept definitions for
						<ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/concepts-6.htm">
						<citetitle>Editor</citetitle></ulink>, <ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/concepts-5.htm">
						<citetitle>View</citetitle></ulink>, and <ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/concepts-4.htm">
						<citetitle>Perspective</citetitle></ulink>.
					</para>
		<para>The Tracker Perspective organizes the workbench into four areas, outlined in colors in
		the above figure. </para>
		<para>
			<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
				<listitem>
					<para>The resource navigation area, highlighted in yellow, provides is the 
					standard Resource Navigator view which presents the tree of Projects, Folders, 
					Files and other resources in the workspace.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>An area for visualizing editors, highlighted in red, where Tracker 
					Document Editors and other Resource Editors display.
					<note><title>Optional Editors</title>
					<para>Displayed is the optional Premises Editor that may be installed 
					(called <glossterm>provisioned</glossterm>) by the user.</para>
					</note>
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The <ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-30.htm">
						<citetitle>Outline View</citetitle></ulink>
						, highlighted in green, displays an outline of a structured 
					file that is currently open in the editor area, and lists structural elements.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The support views area, highlighted in blue, displays the Properties, 
					Console, Problems, Tasks, Queries, Readers, Animals, and Events views.
					<note><title>Optional Views</title>
					<para>The Queries, Readers, Animals, and Events views are optional views that 
					may be provisioned by the user.</para>
					</note>
					</para>
					<para>The <ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-29.htm">
						<citetitle>Properties View</citetitle></ulink> displays read-only information, such as the 
					properties of a file resource and information that can be edited, 
					such as the properties of an Entry in a Document.</para>
					<para>The Console View displays program output information, such as error or 
					warning messages.</para>
					<para>The Problems View displays problems related to workbench or resources.</para>
					<para>The Tasks View displays user reminders of things to do. </para>
					<para>The Ocl Queries View displays a list of quick selection mechanisms for 
					selecting and find information in Tracker Documents.</para>
					<para>The Readers View displays a list of configured Tag ID Readers.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
		
	</section>
	</section>
</chapter>