<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DockBook XML V4.5//EN" 
			"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">

<chapter id="DesktopProduct">
    <?dbhtml filename="desktopProduct/desktopProduct.html" ?>
	<title>Desktop Product</title>
	
    <section id="Overview">
	<title>Overview</title>
	
	<section>
		<title>What is the Tracker Desktop Product?</title>
	<para>The Tracker Desktop Product is an <emphasis>Open Source</emphasis> Livestock Information Browser descended 
	from the Tracker Information Framework suite of products and managed by Verticon, Inc. 
	Tracker Desktop is based on the Eclipse Rich Client Platform, the Eclipse Modeling 
	Framework and OSGi technologies.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="Definitions">
	<?dbhtml filename="overview/desktopOverview_definitions.html" ?>
	<title>Workbench Instances, Workspaces, and Projects</title>
		<para>The main focus of activity in the Tracker Application is the editing of Animal Premises Documents.  In order to discuss the mechanics of editing Tracker Animal Premises Documents, some definitions are in order:
		<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
			    <listitem>
					<para>A Tracker <emphasis>installation</emphasis>  is a location on your disk 
					that contains a distribution of the Tracker. When you unpack a Tracker distribution 
					to a location on your disk, you effectively create a local platform installation at 
					that location. The installation contains a set of tools that were packaged together 
					by the organization that created the distribution. Each of the tools in the platform 
					installation contributes some functionality to the Tracker. You may have several 
					platform installations on your machine, each of which may contain a different set of 
					tools. </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>A Tracker <emphasis>workbench instance</emphasis> is a runtime instance of the 
					Tracker. Every time you launch the Tracker, a workbench instance is created, making 
					the tools in the platform installation from which the instance was loaded available 
					for use.  
					</para>
					<para> For more information, see the Workbook User Guide concept definition for
						<ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/concepts-2.htm"><citetitle>Workbench</citetitle></ulink>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>A Tracker <emphasis>workspace</emphasis> is a location on your disk that is 
					associated with a running workbench instance. It contains the resources (Tracker 
					Documents, files, folders, etc.) that comprise the <emphasis>projects</emphasis> you 
					work on. The tools contained in the platform installation from which the workbench 
					instance was launched can be used to work with the projects in the workspace. Each 
					workbench instance has exclusive access to its associated workspace: concurrently 
					running workbench instances can not share the same workspace. </para>
				</listitem>
				
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		
	</section>
	<section id="Perspective">
	    <?dbhtml filename="overview/desktopOverview_perspective.html" ?>
		<title>Perspective, Editors and Views</title>
		
		<para>Within the Tracker Workbench, Documents are edited, manipulated, and examined with 
		data model specific Document Editors and Views.  To assist you as you work with Documents, 
		a Tracker <emphasis>Perspective</emphasis> visualizes and positions these Tracker specific 
		Editors and Views within the Workbench as shown in <xref 
		linkend="fig_ExcludeResultPrefixesContentAssist1"/>.
       </para>
       <figure id="fig_ExcludeResultPrefixesContentAssist1">
                <title>Tracker Perspective
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/overview/fullScreenShot.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
        </figure>
		<para> For more information, see the Workbook User Guide concept definitions for
						<ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/concepts-6.htm">
						<citetitle>Editor</citetitle></ulink>, <ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/concepts-5.htm">
						<citetitle>View</citetitle></ulink>, and <ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/concepts-4.htm">
						<citetitle>Perspective</citetitle></ulink>.
					</para>
		<para>The Tracker Perspective organizes the workbench into four areas, outlined in colors in
		the above figure. </para>
		<para>
			<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
				<listitem>
					<para>The resource navigation area, highlighted in yellow, provides is the 
					standard Resource Navigator view which presents the tree of Projects, Folders, 
					Files and other resources in the workspace.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>An area for visualizing editors, highlighted in red, where Tracker 
					Document Editors<footnote id="fnrex1b">
					<para>Displayed is the optional Premises Editor that may be installed 
					(called <glossterm>provisioned</glossterm>) by the user.</para>
					</footnote>
					and other Resource Editors display.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The <ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-30.htm">
						<citetitle>Outline View</citetitle></ulink>
						, highlighted in green, displays an outline of a structured 
					file that is currently open in the editor area, and lists structural elements.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The support views area, highlighted in blue, is where the Properties, 
					Console, Problems, Tasks, Ocl Queries<footnote id="fnrex1a">
					<para>An optional feature that may be provisioned by the user.</para>
					</footnote>, Readers<footnoteref linkend="fnrex1a"/>, views are displayed.</para>
					<para>The <ulink url="PLUGINS_ROOT/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/reference/ref-29.htm">
						<citetitle>Properties View</citetitle></ulink> displays read-only information, such as the 
					properties of a file resource and information that can be edited, 
					such as the properties of an Entry in a Document.</para>
					<para>The Console View displays program output information, such as error or 
					warning messages.</para>
					<para>The Problems View displays problems related to workbench or resources.</para>
					<para>The Tasks View displays user reminders of things to do. </para>
					<para>The Ocl Queries View<footnoteref linkend="fnrex1a"/> displays a list of 
					quick selection mechanisms for selecting and find information in 
					Tracker Documents.</para>
					<para>The Readers View<footnoteref linkend="fnrex1a"/> displays a list of 
					configured Tag ID Readers.</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
		
	</section>
	</section>
</chapter>