<?xml version='1.0' encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <?dbhtml filename="fairEditor/fairEditor.html" ?>
  <title>Fair Editor</title>

  <section id="overviewFairEditor">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <section id="overviewFairEditorWhatis">
      <title>What is the Fair Editor?</title>
      <para>The Fair Editor is a comprehensive open desktop solution for documenting, managing, reporting and
      exchanging information associated with livestock animal fairs and expositions.  The Fair Editor is used for
      creating and editing documents that conform to the Fair information (data) model. Fair documents extend
      and compliment livestock animal history information held in Premises documents with 
      fair exhibits, exhibitors, youth clubs, awards, and exhibitor parents information.</para>
    </section>
    <section id="overviewFairEditorGoals">
      <title>Project Goals</title>
      <para>Livestock fairs and animal expositions are special kinds of livestock premises where the 
      information associated with people, clubs, animals, exhibits, contest activities, and awards are recorded and 
      managed.  The goal of the Tracker Fair Editor is to create a comprehensive desktop based software application 
      for Livestock fairs and expositions. An application that:
      <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>
      imports external data from diverse sources</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem><para>
      adds interactive editors and views to record and visualize people and exhibit information
      </para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>
      acts as a data source to leverage powerful reporting tools for creating easy to understand reports
      </para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      
      </para>
       <para>Extending the Tracker Premises livestock suite of tools to address animal livestock 
       fairs and expositions is the primary goal of the Fair Editor project.</para>
      <para>
        The Fair Editor provide models, editors, utilities, views and services for the 
        creation and management of documents that:
        <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
          <listitem>
            <para>Offer bulk data input of exhibitor names, contacts, clubs and parents information</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Leverage full capabilities of the Tracker Premises Editor for managing animal life data and event histories
            for all animals that move in and out of the fair</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Model and visualize contact information for people associated with the fair, including 
            exhibitors, supervisors, judges and parents of the exhibitors</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Model and visualize animal exhibits as the principle relationship between livestock animal life data, animal history, people contact information,
            contests and awards</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Record check-in of livestock animals from source livestock premises for early weigh in and at fair time</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Record weight and full livestock animal <emphasis>life data</emphasis></para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Offer comprehensive electronic interfacing of weight scales and RFID readers for efficient 
            keyboard free inputing of data</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Dynamically calculate average daily gains of animal weights based on previous check-in weights</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Locate Animals that have moved to exhibits within sub-locations of a fair premises</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Resolve Animal locations that have moved to another premises after check-in or at the end of the fair.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Assign animal exhibit positions based on visual sighting records or data inputs from industry standard GPS 
            devices</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>Act as a data source for a full featured Business Intelligence Reporting Tool <acronym>BIRT</acronym> 
            for batch and ad-hoc report generation 
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section id="overviewFairFunctional">
      <title>Functional Overview</title>
      <para>The Fair Editor is used to create documents that manage information for livestock fairs and expositions.</para>
      <note>
        <para>The Fair Editor requires installation of the Premises Editor Feature.</para>
        <para>If location visualization and location resolution services are desired, the Agriculture and Geography 
        Features may be installed.</para> 
      </note>
       <para>
      The Fair Editor extends the Tracker Premises Editor by integrating a new fair specific data model, 
      views for managing people and exhibits, editors for creating documents, and utilities for importing 
      people, youth club and exhibit information.</para>
      <para>The Tracker Editor offers:
        <itemizedlist mark="bullet">
         <listitem>
            <para>
              Support for pre-fair preparation:
              <itemizedlist>
               <listitem>
            		<para>Utilities for importing tag numbers from external files</para>
          		</listitem>
          		<listitem>
           			 <para>Utilities for importing people contact information from external files</para>
          		</listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </para>
          </listitem>
          
          <listitem>
            <para>
              Support for pre-fair weigh-in:
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Recording exhibitor information</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Recording life data and the source premises of animals</para>
                </listitem>
                 <listitem>
                  <para>Manual or electronic recording animal weights</para>
                </listitem>
                 <listitem>
                  <para>Registering exhibitors for each animal</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Printing registration summary reports for exhibitors</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </para>
          </listitem>
           <listitem>
            <para>
              Support for check in fair use-cases:
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Simple tag scan to check-in animal</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Manual or electronic recording animal fair registration weights</para>
                </listitem>
                 <listitem>
                  <para>Automatic calculation of average daily weight gain based on pre-fair weigh-in</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>Assignment or reassignment exhibits to appropriate lots and/or classes</para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
            </para>
          </listitem>
           <listitem>
                  <para>Support for fair judging and awards</para>
           </listitem>
           <listitem>
                  <para>Support for fair check out</para>
           </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  
  <section id="fairDocuments">
   <?dbhtml filename="model/fairEditorModel_FairDocuments.html" ?>
    <title>Fair Documents</title>
    <para>The Fair Editor enables users to create, transform and 
    edit documents referencing animals, exhibts and people within a Premises.</para>
     <para>Fair document files utilize a <code>.fair</code> file extension to 
    distinguish them from other types of files.</para>
  </section>
 
  <section id="editingFairDocuments">
    	<?dbhtml filename="editingFairDocuments/editingFairDocuments.html" ?>
		<title>Editing Fair Documents</title>
		<section id="creatingFairDocuments">
			<title>Creating a new Fair Document</title>
			<para>
			To create a new Fair document. Go to the File menu and launch a 
			<emphasis>New Fair Document Wizard</emphasis> by selecting the menu items:<code>File|New|Fair Document</code>.
			</para>

		<para>Follow the instructions to choose a project, folder and a name for the document.
		Select <code>Fair</code> as the model object and press <code>Finish</code> to create the document. 
			
		</para>
       <figure id="fig_selectFairModelObject">
			<title>New Fair Document Wizard Model Object Prompt</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/selectModelObject.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		</section>
		
		<section id="loadingPremisesDocumentResources">
		<?dbhtml filename="editingFairDocuments/loadingFairDocuments.html" ?>
		<title>Loading Additional Resources into the Document</title>
		 <note>
			<para>
				Since the Fair document references the Premises element of a Tracker Premises document, 
				a Premises document resources must already exist in the workspace.  If it does not, create
				a empty Premises document first. <emphasis>You can always add data to the referenced 
				Premises document at the same time you edit the Fair document.</emphasis>
			</para>
		 </note>
			<para>
			To reference a <code>Premises</code> element from a Fair document, a Premises document must first be loaded 
			into the Fair document as a resource. 
			To load a Premises document as a resource place the mouse cursor on the root element in the Fair document, 
			right click, and from the pull down menu choose <code>Load Resorce...</code>
			</para>
			<figure id="fig_loadFairResource">
			<title>Load Resource Dialog</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/loadResource.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>From the dialog choose the Premises document that you wish to load.</para>
			<figure id="fig_loadedFairResource">
			<title>Fair Project with Loaded Resources</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/loadedResources.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			</figure>
	    <para>When Premises documents are loaded as a resource in a Fair document, the editor choice boxes 
	    associated with the <code>Premises</code> attribute of the <code>Fair</code> element will be shown
	    as a choice for user selection. 
	   </para>
	 </section>

     <section id="openingFairDocument">
	    <?dbhtml filename="editingFairDocuments/openingFairDocuments.html" ?>
	    <title>Opening a Fair Document</title>
	    <para>For high throughput during fair weigh-ins and check-ins the Fair Transaction Editor can be used to
	    edit fair documents.  The Fair Transaction Editor supports the Tracker 
	    <emphasis>Transaction</emphasis> processing facility for electronic input of data originating from
	    network connected sensors and RFID readers.
	   </para>
	   <para>To open a Fair document with the Fair Transaction Editor, right click on the Fair document and 
	   select the pull down menu item <code>Open With</code>.</para>
	   <figure id="fig_openingFairDocuments">
			<title>Opening a Fair Transaction Editor</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/editing/fairTransactionEditor.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
	   </figure>
	   <note><para>When not working with RFID readers or sensors, it is best to use the basic Fair 
	   Editor.</para></note>
	    </section>

	</section>
	
  <section id="fairActions">
		<?dbhtml filename="fairActions/fairActions.html" ?>
		<title>Fair Action Commands</title>
		<para>For key elements within the Fair document, and the associated Premises document the Fair Editor provides 
		action commands that the user can invoke to effect changes on the content of the information held in these documents.
		</para>
		
		<para>Fair Actions can be invoked on Fair document elements and for elements in the associated Premises document
		<footnote><para>In addition to the actions that the Fair Editor adds to Premises elements the user will also see
		the actions that the Premises Editor and other provisioned features have added to the Premises elements. 
		</para></footnote>. 
		These actions may be accessed as popup menus on the Fair and Premises document elements when viewing documents in 
		the Fair Editor, document tree in the Outline View tree, the master table of the Exhibit View, the master table 
		of the People View, the master table in the Animals View or the master table of the Events View. 
	    <footnote><para> 
		Right click on the element and the popup main menu will be shown. From there the sub menu 'Tracker Actions' will 
		contain the appropriate action command.
			</para></footnote>
		
			<figure id="fig_fair_actions_selection">
                <title>Invoking Element Actions from Fair Editor
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/actions/editor.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
        	</figure>
        	
        	<figure id="fig_fair_actions_animals">
                <title>Invoking Element Actions from People View Master Table
                </title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata align="center"
                            fileref="../images/actions/people.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
        	</figure>
		
			<table id = 'allElementsActions' frame='all'>
				<title>Action Commands on all Elements</title>
				<tgroup cols='9' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
					<colspec colname='c1' /><!-- Target -->
					<colspec colname='c2' />
					<colspec colname='c3' />
					<colspec colname='c4' />
					<colspec colname='c5' />
					<colspec colname='c6' />
					<colspec colname='c7' />
					<colspec colname='c8' />
					<colspec colname='c9' />
					
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>Element</entry>
							<entry>Command Name</entry>
							<entry>Fair Editor<footnote><para>The Outline View like the Selection Page of the Premises Editor
							shows the document as a tree.  All actions that can be accessed as popup menus in the Selection Page 
							are also available from the Outline View.</para></footnote></entry>
							<entry>From People View</entry>
							<entry>From Exhibits View</entry>
							<entry>From Animals View</entry>
							<entry>From Events View</entry>
							<entry>Description</entry>
							<entry>Comment</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry>All elements</entry>
							<entry>Select Element(s) in Outline View</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							
							<entry>
								Selects the same element or elements in the tree of the Outline View. 
							</entry>
							
							<entry>Helpful to sync from Views to the context of a tree view.</entry>
						</row>
						
						<row>
							<entry>All elements</entry>
							<entry>Context Free Query<footnote><para>Only availible when the OCL feature is provisioned.</para></footnote></entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							
							<entry>
								Shows a dialog for entry of a query to select sub (child) elements of the selection.
							</entry>
							
							<entry>From a Fair or Premises element enter a query to find exhibits, people, animals or events. 
							<footnote><para>See the OCL Query documentation for more details.</para></footnote></entry>
						</row>
						
						<row>
							<entry>All elements</entry>
							<entry>Query with Context<footnote><para>Only availible when the OCL feature is provisioned.</para></footnote></entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							
							<entry>
								Shows a dialog for entry of a query to select sub (child) elements of the selection. A 
								combo box for selection of the query context.
							</entry>
							
							<entry>Select the Fair or Premises and query to find exhibits, people, animals or events.</entry>
						</row>
						
						
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</table>


			<table id='peopleAnimalsAndLotActions' frame='all'>
				<title>Action Commands on Person, Animals, and Lots</title>
				<tgroup cols='9' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
					<colspec colname='c1' /><!-- Target -->
					<colspec colname='c2' />
					<colspec colname='c3' />
					<colspec colname='c4' />
					<colspec colname='c5' />
					<colspec colname='c6' />
					<colspec colname='c7' />
					<colspec colname='c8' />
					<colspec colname='c9' />
					
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>Element</entry>
							<entry>Command Name</entry>
							<entry>Fair Editor<footnote><para>The Outline View like the Selection Page of the Premises Editor
							shows the document as a tree.  All actions that can be accessed as popup menus in the Selection Page 
							are also available from the Outline View.</para></footnote></entry>
							<entry>From People View</entry>
							<entry>From Exhibits View</entry>
							<entry>From Animals View</entry>
							<entry>From Events View</entry>
							<entry>Description</entry>
							<entry>Comment</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<!-- Change Move Event Pins -->
						<row>
							<entry>Person(s)</entry>
							<entry>Update Pins on all Exhibited Animal Events</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							
							<entry>
								Persons pin value is set on all the moved events of his exhibited Animals 
							</entry>
							
							<entry>Helpful when the pin value is only known after the events take place.</entry>
						</row>
						
						<!-- Copy Person -->
						<row>
							<entry>Person(s)</entry>
							<entry>Copy Person</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							
							<entry>
								Takes the information from one person element and duplicate it for a new person element.
							</entry>
							
							<entry>Helpful when a family is registering to copy all addressing and parent information to a sibling.</entry>
						</row>
						<!-- Register Exhibit -->
						
						<!-- Copy Person -->
						<row>
							<entry>Animal(s) with optional selections for Person and Lot</entry>
							<entry>Register in Exhibit</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>No</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							<entry>Yes</entry>
							
							<entry>
								Registers one or more animals in exhibits for a person.
							</entry>
							
							<entry>Helpful during registration of exhibits.<footnote><para>Once a person and their animals are added to the system, 
							select the group of animals, the person, the lot to register them in,
							an invoke this command. It will create the exhibit.  One or more animals are required 
							for the selection. If the person or the lot is not included in the selection
							a wizard dialog will prompt the user for the missing information, either the 
							person, the lot or both.</para></footnote></entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</table>
		</para>
	</section>

  <section id="fairDataModel">
    <?dbhtml filename="model/fairEditorModel_agricultureDataModel.html" ?>
    <title>Fair Data Model</title>
    <para>Because all user activity centers around the creation and 
    manipulation of <emphasis>Fair Documents</emphasis>, 
    understanding the structure (called the <glossterm>data 
    model</glossterm>) of Fair documents is the easiest way to 
    learn to use the information management facilities of the Fair 
    Editor.</para>
    <section id="fairDataModel_coreElements">
      <title>Fair Data Model Core Elements</title>
      <para>All Fair documents conform to a very simple structure called the
      <emphasis>Fair Data Model</emphasis>. In the Fair Data 
      Model, a single Fair element is given a name and a reference to a Tracker Premises file.
	  Within this Fair element Youth Clubs, People, and Divisions of Exhibits are created by the operator.</para>
      <para>Core elements of the Fair Data Model are shown in 
      <xref linkend="fig_FairCoreDataModel"/>.</para>
      <figure id="fig_FairCoreDataModel">
        <title>Fair Core Data Model Elements</title>
        <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
         fileref="../images/model/fairCore.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
      </figure>
      <para>
        <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
          <listitem>
            <para>The core elements of the Core Model are depicted 
            as rectangles in the figure.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The notation within the elements are the attributes 
            of the element.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>The notation between the elements are the 
            relationships of the elements.</para>
          </listitem>
        </orderedlist>
      </para>
      <para>
        The following table offers a text explanation of the Element 
        Relationships.
        <table frame="all">
          <title>Core Elements of the Premises Model</title>
          <tgroup align="left" cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
            <colspec colname="c1"/>
            <colspec colname="c2"/>
            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>Element Name</entry>
                <entry>Relationship to other Elements</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Fair</entry>
                <entry>There is one Fair element. It acts as the first or root element of the document</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>name attribute</entry>
                <entry>A Fair has a name that is assigned by the operator</entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>premises attribute</entry>
                <entry>A Fair has a premises attribute to reference the Premises document that will contain all the animal information</entry>
              </row>
               <row>
                <entry>Person Elements</entry>
                <entry>Fair has one or more person elements that are used to document people contact information. A fair document can specify 
                people as exhibitors, parents, supervisors and judges. 
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>Youth Club Elements</entry>
                <entry>Exhibitors can be assigned to groups called Youth Clubs. </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>Exhibits</entry>
                <entry>Exhibits are assigned within a hierarchy of Divisions, Departments, Classes and Lot containers. See the   
      				<xref linkend="fig_ExhibitHierarchy"/> for the diagram showing how the hierarchy contains multiple child elements.</entry>
              </row>
              
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
      </para>
      
      
      <figure id="fig_ExhibitHierarchy">
			<title>Hierarchy of Exhibits</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center"
						fileref="../images/model/exhibitHierarchy.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
      
      
    </section>
  </section>
  
  <section id="fairEditor_useCase">
  <?dbhtml filename="usecase/fairEditor_useCase.html" ?>
    <title>Fair Editor Use Cases</title>
    <para>To best depict what the Fair Editor can do for Tracker users, the following figure presents a overview of
    the <emphasis>Use-Cases</emphasis> that can be performed. </para>
    <para>
    <xref linkend="fig_FairEditorUseCases"/> shows an overview of the usage 
    requirements for the Fair Editor.</para>
    <figure id="fig_FairEditorUseCases">
      <title>Fair Editor Overview</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
       fileref="../images/useCases/editor.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <note><para>Typically one Fair document and a referenced Premises document are the only two documents necessary for 
    recording all uses-cases given for a fair.  Youth club and person contacts can easily be copied and pasted from one 
    year to the next.</para></note>
  
  <section id="preFair_useCase">
  <?dbhtml filename="usecase/preFair_useCase.html" ?>
    <title>Prefair Use Cases</title>
    <para>Preparing for the fair is a simple matter of pre-allocating groups of tags to certain animal types,
    importing any people contact information that may already exist and setting up the types of 
    contests that will make up the fair.</para>
    <para>
    <xref linkend="fig_PreFairUseCases"/> shows pre-fair usage 
    requirements for the Fair Editor.</para>
    <figure id="fig_PreFairUseCases">
      <title>Preparing for the fair</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
       fileref="../images/useCases/preFairUseCases.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  
  <section id="weighIn_useCase">
  <?dbhtml filename="usecase/weighIn_useCase.html" ?>
    <title>WeighIn Use Cases</title>
    <para>Many Fairs hold a early season weigh-in of animals in order to show an average daily weight gain.</para>
    <para> 
    <xref linkend="fig_WeighInUseCases"/> shows early weigh-in usage 
    requirements for the Fair Editor.</para>
    <figure id="fig_WeighInUseCases">
      <title>Animal Weigh-In</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
       fileref="../images/useCases/weighIn.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  
   <section id="fairCheckIn_useCase">
  <?dbhtml filename="usecase/fairCheckIn_useCase.html" ?>
    <title>Check-In Use Cases</title>
    <para>Checking in animals to the fair is often a two-fold process.  First there is the veterinarian check to 
    insure that the animal is healthy and has all required papers. Next the animal is checked in.</para>
    <para>
    <xref linkend="fig_FairCheckInUseCases"/> shows early check-in usage 
    requirements for the Fair Editor.</para>
    <figure id="fig_FairCheckInUseCases">
      <title>Animal Check-In</title>
      <mediaobject><imageobject><imagedata align="center"
       fileref="../images/useCases/fairCheckIn.png"/></imageobject></mediaobject>
    </figure>
  </section>
  
  </section>
  
</chapter>
