<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
 "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  	<?dbhtml filename="overview/frameworkUseCases.html" ?>
	<title>Use Cases</title>
	
	<section>
	<?dbhtml filename="overview/frameworkOverview_useCaseDiagrams.html" ?>
		<title>Tracker Solution Use-Cases</title>
		<para>
		This section utilizes <emphasis>use-case diagrams</emphasis> to describe 
		Tracker functionality from the users<footnote>
		<para>Users of Tracker are typically Livestock <emphasis>Producers</emphasis> 
		operating the Tracker Desktop applications, but they may also be auditors, infrastructure providers or
		Livestock Information Analysts.  The section will use the terminology <emphasis>Operator</emphasis>
		and <emphasis>Information Technology Analyst</emphasis> to distinguish between field operators and information
		analysts.</para>
		</footnote> point of view. Tracker user functionality can be organized 
		into the following six categories:
		<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Data Collection;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Documentation;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Management;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Analysis;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Reporting;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						and Collaboration.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<note>
			 <para>
				To accommodate the largest number of users, in the most open way possible,
				Tracker applications support multiple Operating Systems.  Tracker application 
				runtime binaries are available for the following leading Operating System 
				platforms:
				<itemizedlist mark='arabic'>
				<listitem>
					<para>Microsoft <trademark>Windows</trademark>;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Linux;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>and Apple <trademark>MacOS</trademark>.</para>
				</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				</para>
			</note>
		</para>
		
		
		<section>
		    <?dbhtml filename="overview/frameworkOverview_useCaseDiagrams_dataCollection.html" ?>
			<title>Data Collection</title>
			<para>
				Offering a value added suite of information solutions to livestock professionals initially
				requires the collection of a diverse data set prior to processing and reporting. 
			</para>
			<para>
				Tracker provides three ways to collect livestock data:
				<itemizedlist mark='arabic'>
				<listitem>
					<para>manual data entry by the Tracker operator;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>importation of bulk data from external files;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>and input of real-time electronic transactions from sensors and readers.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			Data Collection functionality is shown in the <xref linkend="fig_DataCollectionUseCases" />
			<footnote>
			<para>
				More detailed use-case diagrams are documented in the latter chapters on 
				Provisioned Editors and Features. 
			</para>
			</footnote>. 
		
			<figure id="fig_DataCollectionUseCases">
				<title>Data Collection Use-Case Diagram</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/useCases/dataCollection.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
	
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section>
		    <?dbhtml filename="overview/frameworkOverview_useCaseDiagrams_documentation.html" ?>
			<title>Documentation</title>
			<para>
				After data is collected, the collected data itself needs to be structured, consolidated and 
				persisted.   Next users need to confirm that the results of this process is a 
				<emphasis>valid model</emphasis> of the real world process they are trying to 
				capture.   
			</para>
			<para>
				Tracker applications consolidate, structure and persist data to light weight
				<ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XMI">industry standard</ulink> document files. 
				Since files can be attached and sent via email or other file sharing technologies using 
				standard based document files for data storage provides Tracker users significant 
				benefits over storing data in heavy weight relational databases or proprietary document 
				formats.  If business requirements dictate the need for multi-user data storage or the storage of
			    large volumes of premises data, the optional Tracker Store feature offers an easy to deploy,
			    robust and highly scalable data storage solution. 
				<footnote> 
				<para>
					Industry standard text based data documents offer greater mobility than database data storage 
					and greater processing, tooling, analysis, reporting and collaborating
				    options than proprietary document formats.  Open standard document formats are the key
				    to many of the subsequent use-case scenarios presented in this section.
				</para>
				<para>
					This documentation uses the term <emphasis>Tracker Data Documents</emphasis> as a 
					shorthand for the more technically precise term 
					<emphasis><ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/modeling/emf/">EMF Ecore</ulink> 
					Model Instance</emphasis> document.  
				</para>
				</footnote>.
			</para>  
			<para>
				Structuring and consolidating data to documents is the first step of the process, but 
				users need tools to confirm that documents are <emphasis>valid</emphasis> models of real world 
				processes.  For the document to be considered valid for a real world 
				process, rules for judging validity must be controlled by the user.<footnote>
				<para>Document validation basically insures that data contained in documents 
				meet user requirements. Since user requirements may change based on a specific project or 
				livestock scenario, the user must be able to modify and change these rules. </para>
				</footnote>	
			</para>
			<para>
			Documentation functionality is shown in the <xref linkend="fig_DocumentationUseCases" />	
				<figure id="fig_DocumentationUseCases">
				<title>Documentation Use-Case Diagram</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/useCases/documentation.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section>
		    <?dbhtml filename="overview/frameworkOverview_useCaseDiagrams_management.html" ?>
			<title>Management</title>
			<para>
				Tracker data documents are created and used within a specific livestock 
				business context. Within this context Tracker documents are often associated 
				with other files and folders of files. 
				<footnote>
				<para>
				For example: Tracker data documents may be associated with the raw data files that 
				were initially imported into the Tracker documents; Tracker data documents are 
				often accompanied by report design files used for running reports; and there 
				may even be multiple Tracker document files associated with different data
				viewpoints of a particular work activity.  
				</para>
				</footnote>
			</para>
			<para>
				To address the requirement for grouping files into work contexts
				Tracker supports the concept of a <emphasis>Project</emphasis>.
				<footnote>
				<para>
					Eclipse also supports a higher or parent level of container above that of a project 
					container. This higher level container is called an Eclipse <emphasis>workspace</emphasis>
					and it exists to hold user settings and contain multiple projects. 
					A Tracker user can work with Multiple Workspaces each containing multiple Projects. 
					For the typical Tracker user, they can elect to only use the default
					workspace and afterwards ignore the concept of workspaces.  
				</para>
				</footnote>
			</para>
			  
			<para>
				A Tracker project is a conceptual container for managing <emphasis>related</emphasis> files, folders, 
				documents, reports and images. Files in Tracker projects can be created, organized in folders, 
				removed, deleted and edited. Files in Tracker Projects can also be compared to each other and 
				the editing histories of files can also be viewed and changes compared. Projects (and all the contained
				files) can be archived, exported, and imported into the Tracker.<footnote>
				<para>Tracker also supports simple project management tools for managing ToDo tasks and network
				backup of projects. Tools 
				for more sophisticated project management and file revision control are available as Eclipse
				features that can also be added to the Tracker.</para>
				</footnote>
			</para>
			<para>
			Management functionality is shown in the <xref linkend="fig_ManagementUseCases" />	
				<figure id="fig_ManagementUseCases">
				<title>Management Use-Case Diagram</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/useCases/management.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section>
		    <?dbhtml filename="overview/frameworkOverview_useCaseDiagrams_analysis.html" ?>
			<title>Analysis and Reporting</title>
			<para>
				To create information useful to end users, Tracker data documents can be used as data 
				sources to 
				<ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/birt/phoenix/intro/">Eclipse Business Intelligence Reporting Tool</ulink>
				<acronym>(BIRT)</acronym> reports.
				<footnote><para>TrackerStore can also be used as a data source for BIRT reports.</para> </footnote>
			</para>
			
			<para>
				BIRT reports are created by Livestock Information Technology Analysts.
				<footnote>
				<para>Also called Business Analysts or Report Designers.</para>
				</footnote>
			    After analyzing specific livestock information problems these analysts 
				utilize the BIRT Report Designer tool to specify how to extract and create information from 
				Tracker data documents.  These specifications result in a set of BIRT report 
				design documents and report libraries.  Report design documents and libraries  
				are distributed to Tracker End Users who use them to run reports against one or more 
				data documents in order to visualize and export information. <footnote>
				<para>Tracker end users would be able to run reports but would not have access
				to the Report Designer tool.  
				</para>
				</footnote> 
			</para>
			
			<para>
				In addition to enabling Tracker users to run reports against Tracker data documents, Information
				Technology Analysts can further enable Tracker End Users by crafting report based solutions
				that integrate data from Tracker data documents and any other source of BIRT data.  
				Besides Tracker data documents BIRT reports can access and visualize data from:
			    <orderedlist numeration="arabic">
					<listitem><para>SQL Relational Databased through any JDBC driver;</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Eclipse Modeling Framework EMF Ecore data models;</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Non-standard data models through custom code;</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>Flat file data using standard delimiters;</para></listitem>
					<listitem><para>XML files or streams using XPath syntax to specify columns. </para></listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para>
			<para>
			Analysis and Reporting functionality is shown in the <xref linkend="fig_AnalysisReportingUseCases" />	
				<figure id="fig_AnalysisReportingUseCases">
				<title>Analysis and Reporting Use-Case Diagram</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/useCases/analysisReporting.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section>
		    <?dbhtml filename="overview/frameworkOverview_useCaseDiagrams_collaboration.html" ?>
			<title>Collaboration</title>
			<para>
				Because Tracker data documents are small industry standard data containers they are ideal 
				for exchanging and sharing <emphasis>validated</emphasis> livestock information. Tracker 
				documents are easily shared between individual users, groups of users, business collaborators 
				and central auditing authorities.
				<footnote>
				<para>BIRT reports can also easily be created and shared with other users and collaborators.</para>
				</footnote>
			</para>
			
			<para>Collaboration technology options range from manual file over media transfers,
				<footnote>
				<para>
					For example documents or document fragments can be exchanged on usb flash drives or flash memory 
					cards.
				</para>
				</footnote>
			to common Internet file transfer utilities,
			<footnote>
			<para>Email, FTP, and Web Server uploading and downloading.</para>
			</footnote> 
			to a mediated collaboration service that offers publish and request services to Tracker clients.
			<footnote>
			 <para>
			 The TrackerStore is an example of such a service. One or more TrackerStore Collaboration Service Providers could be utilized by Tracker clients. Example administrators
			 of these service providers could be industry associations or government auditing authorities.
			 </para>
			 </footnote>.
			</para>
 
			<para>
			Collaboration functionality is shown in the <xref linkend="fig_CollaborationUseCases" />	
				<figure id="fig_CollaborationUseCases">
				<title>Collaboration Use-Case Diagram</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="../images/useCases/collaboration.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
	
