<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" 
 "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  	<?dbhtml filename="editors/editors.html" ?>
	<title>Provisioned Editors</title>
	<para>Livestock producers, processors and auditors require tools for
	modeling, recording, editing, and reporting on livestock operational information. These tools
	must be able to meet requirements common to each type of livestock operation but also be capable of adapting to 
	specific use cases. For each use case the essential consideration is how to structure 
	or <emphasis>model</emphasis> the operational data to ensure vital information can be 
	efficiently captured, stored, analyzed, and utilized in a operationally valuable way.
	</para>
	
	<para>Common operational use cases are analyzed, then modeled by Tracker business analysts resulting
	in concise <emphasis>data model</emphasis> specifications.  From these data model specifications 
	Tracker engineers craft use case specific editors, tools, and utilities which are then
    delivered as Tracker features to end users.
	</para>
	
	<para>Tracker Business Intelligence Features
	consist of the following data model specific editors:
	<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
				<listitem>
				  <para>Premises Editor, is the primary Tracker Livestock editor and its associated data model 
						is often extended by the other data model editors;
				  </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					 <para>The Geography Editor is an open source desktop solution for authoring, managing and integrating
      					state of the art Geographic Information System <acronym>GIS</acronym> technologies based on the 
      					<ulink url="http://www.opengeospatial.org/"> <citetitle>OpenGIS</citetitle></ulink> 
      					Key Hole Markup Language <acronym>KML</acronym>;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Fair Editor, extends the Premises Editor to model and document people and animals at a 
						Livestock Exhibition. The Premises Editor and the Fair Editor are the initial Tracker editors.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Metatype Model Editor, is a used to create configuration documents that extend the 
					functionality of core Tracker Features;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Agriculture Editor is a solution for documenting, managing and visualizing geographic livestock herd distributions, individual 
      				animal locations, and animal movements within and between premises locations.</para>
      				<para>The Agriculture Editor and Location Service is a suite of tools that integrates state of 
      				the art Geographic Information System <acronym>GIS</acronym> technologies based on the 
      				<ulink url="http://www.opengeospatial.org/"> <citetitle>OpenGIS</citetitle></ulink> Key Hole Markup 
     				 Language<acronym>KML</acronym> with Tracker Premises livestock management information;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Custom Editors, are editors used to create customer specific data model documents that
					meet unique customer use-case requirements.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
 		</para>

</chapter>
	
