<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "../docbook-xml/docbookx.dtd" >
<book vendor="Verticon, Inc." label="Tracker User Guide"
	status="Draft">

	<bookinfo>
		<title>Tracker User Guide</title>
		<authorgroup>
			<author>
				<firstname>John</firstname>
				<surname>Conlon</surname>
				<affiliation>
					<orgname>Verticon, Inc.</orgname>
				</affiliation>
			</author>
		</authorgroup>
		<edition>
			Tracker User's Guide version 0.1.0 for Tracker V0.1.0
		</edition>
		<pubdate>September 5, 2007</pubdate>
		<copyright>
			<year>2007</year>
			<year>2006</year>
			<holder>Verticon, Inc.</holder>
		</copyright>

		<legalnotice>
			<blockquote>
				<para>
					Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or
					modify this document under the terms of the GNU Free
					Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later
					version published by the Free Software Foundation;
					with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts,
					and no Back-Cover Texts. A copy of the license is
					included in the section entitled "GNU Free
					Documentation License".
				</para>
			</blockquote>
		</legalnotice>

		<legalnotice>
			<blockquote>
				<para>
					Tracker is free software: you can redistribute it
					and/or modify it under the terms of the
					<acronym>GNU</acronym>
					General Public License as published by the Free
					Software Foundation, either version 3 of the
					License, or (at your option) any later version.

					This program is distributed in the hope that it will
					be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even
					the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS
					FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. See the
					<acronym>GNU</acronym>
					General Public License for more details.
				</para>
				<para>
					A copy of the license is included in the section
					entitled
					<acronym>GNU</acronym>
					General Public License version 3.
				</para>
			</blockquote>
		</legalnotice>

	</bookinfo>
	<preface>
		<title>The Need for Animal Tracking</title>
		<para>
			Either for hunting or husbandry human beings have always
			observed and remembered animal movements. Today, with larger
			herds and more interaction between producers and
			infrastructure providers, more animal movements mean
		    more information for the producer or provider to manage.
		</para>
		<para>
			Computers, software applications and animal event sensors
			that record and manage animal movements and histories
			can ease the information management burden and reduce the
			cost for farm animal producers and livestock infrastructure
			providers.
		</para>
		<para>
			Tracker is used by livestock producers, infrastructure
			providers and process control auditors as an effective, low
			cost solution for;
			<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
			    <listitem>
					<para>recording animal history;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>maintaining production efficiency;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>improving product quality;</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>documenting process control.</para>
				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>
		</para>

	</preface>
	<colophon>
		<para>
			Production versions of this documentation were produced with
			the DocBook DSSSL Stylesheets, called by the Apache Ant build tool,
			from within an Eclipse IDE.
		</para>
	</colophon>

</book>
