<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DockBook XML V4.5//EN" "../docbook-xml/docbookx.dtd" >
<chapter id="ch02">
	<title>Premises Model</title>
	<section>
		<title>Modeling the Animal Premises</title>
		<para>
			Computers can be thought of as mechanisms or containers for
			modeling an aspect of the real world. The Tracker software
			application models the animals and events associated with or
			contained within the premises of a farm or a livestock
			infrastructure provider. The Tracker application uses a
			document paradigm to model an animal premises.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Tracker Model Documents</title>
		<para>
			Whether it is word processing, spreadsheets, or
			presentation, today's computer users are most familiar with
			applications that utilize a document paradigm that create
			documents that represent (model) information.
		</para>
		<para>
			The Tracker enables users to create, transform and edit
			tracker model documents that represent (model) specific
			Animal Premises. Model documents are displayed and
			manipulated with the various Tracker Editors, Wizards, and
			Importing and Exporting utilities. The attributes of the
			premises, the animals in the premises and the events
			associated with animals are specified within these model
			documents. Model document files utilize a .tracker file
			extension to distinguish them from other file.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="ch02dataModel">
		<title>Tracker Data Model</title>
		<para>
			All tracker model documents conform to the Tracker Data
			Model. In the Tracker Data Model a single Premises contains
			0 or more animals. Each Animal must have at least one but
			may have more than one (identification) tags. Each Tag must
			have at least one but may have more than one associated
			events.
		</para>
		<para>
			In the figure below you will find a graphic representation
			of the The Tracker Data Model.
		</para>
		<figure>
			<title>Tracker Data Model Core Elements</title>
			<graphic srccredit="Verticon, Inc., 2007"
				fileref="figures/coreDataModel.png" scale="60" align="left" />
		</figure>
		<para>
			The core elements of the Data Model are depicted as blue
			rectangles in the figure.
			<table frame='all'>
				<title>Core Elements of the Data Model</title>
				<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
					<colspec colname='c1' />
					<colspec colname='c2' />
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>Element Name</entry>
							<entry>
								Relationship to other Elements
							</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry>Premises</entry>
							<entry>
								There is one premises in a document
							</entry>

						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Animal</entry>
							<entry>
								A premises can have zero or many animals
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Tag</entry>
							<entry>
								An Animal can have one or many tags
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry></entry>
							<entry>
								A Premises can have zero or many tags
								that are unassigned
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Event</entry>
							<entry>
								A Tag can have one or many events
							</entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</table>

		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
