<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DockBook XML V4.5//EN" "../docbook-xml/docbookx.dtd" >
<chapter>
	<title>
		Events Manipulation with Templates and Tag IdNumber
		Files
	</title>
	<section>
		<title>Adding Events and Animals to Documents</title>
		<para>
			Although Tracker Editors make it easy to add individual Animals and Events to tracker Documents, adding
			dozens of animals, or hundreds of events to a Premises individually is not practical. For bulk loading 
			of animals and events to a premises model documents Tracker uses Templates, Tag IdNumber files and event 
			manipulation features that simplify the process.
		</para>
		<para>
			Templates represent an event or set of events that can be
			applied to one or more specified animals. To specify which
			animals to apply the template events to, two methods
			are offered:
			<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Directly selecting the animal or a set of
						animals with mouse selections.
						<tip>
							<para>
								Animals call also be selected with <acronym>OCL</acronym> Query operations. 
								See <xref linkend="ch03" />
							</para>
						</tip>
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Indirectly selecting an animal or set of animals
						from lists of Tag/@idNumbers contained in Tag
						IdNumber files. See
						<xref linkend="ch04idNumberFiles" />
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Templates</title>
		<para>
			Templates are model documents similar to *.tracker model documents accept they use
			the *.animal extension.  Template documents are used to contain a default animal, an attached tag,
			and a set of representative events.  Tracker utilities accessible through popup menus allow Templates 
			to be used to add various combinations of animals and/or events to specified sets of animals. 
		</para>
		<para>
			Templates have the following characteristics:
			<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Templates may have an default Animal, a Tag and a set of
						representative events.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Only the Animal element is required in the
						template.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If an Animal and a Tag is included the
						Tag/@idNumber is not considered significant and
						is ignored. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Templates are persisted in files with a *.animal extension.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						All events in a Template are significant and will be copied to 
					 	the specified Animal or a set Animals.
					 </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Timestamps of the template events are considered significant and are
						copied in the events added to specified Animal or set of Animal, unless
						<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
							<listitem>
								<para>
									The tag file name uses the format
									yyMMddHHmmss.tags. For example the
									tags file 060409131111.Tags will set
									the date of all events to 04/09/06
									13:11:11
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									The timestamp year on the event is
									set earlier than 1000 AD, then
									Timestamps of events in the template
									are replaced with the current time.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									Transaction processing of tags
									always use the current timestamp.
								</para>
							</listitem>
						</orderedlist>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="ch04idNumberFiles">
		<title>Tag IdNumber Files</title>
		<para>
			Most tag readers typically output a Tag read as an <acronym>ASCII</acronym> encoded string
			(For more information on ASCII, see the Wikipedia entry for
			<ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASCII"><citetitle>ASCII</citetitle></ulink>) that
			represents the value of a <code>Tag/@idNumber</code>.  The conventional way to deal with multiple tag reads
			is to simply save these lists of <acronym>ASCII</acronym> <code>Tag/@idNumber</code> strings as text files.  
			Tracker calls <code>Tag/@idNumber</code> text files that have been saved with the *.tags extension a 
			<emphasis>Tag IdNumber File</emphasis>.
		</para>
		<para>
			To indicate to Tracker that the read time of the tags in a
			Tag IdNumber file is significant, the name of the tag file
			may be formated to reflect that time. To timestamp a Tag
			IdNumber file use the formating of
			<code>yyMMddHHmmss</code>
			, where
			<simplelist type='horiz' columns='1'>
				<member>yy is the last two digits of the year,</member>
				<member>MM is the month,</member>
				<member>dd is the day of the month,</member>
				<member>
					HH is the hour of the day in 24 hour clock,
				</member>
				<member>mm is the minute of the hour,</member>
				<member>ss is the second</member>
			</simplelist>
			<example>
				<title>A Timestamped Tag IdNumber File Name</title>
				<formalpara>
					<title>060409131111.tags</title>
					<para>
						Specifies the date of all
						<code>Tag/@idNumber</code>
						reads to have occurred at 04/09/06 at 13:11:11.
					</para>
				</formalpara>
			</example>

		</para>
		<tip>
			<para>
				Tag IdNumber Files can also be utilized by the
				transaction infrastructure. See ...
			</para>
		</tip>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Usage and operations</title>
		<section>
			<title>
				Directly Selecting Animals to Add Events
			</title>
			<para>
				To add a series of events to an animal or set of animals
				you will need to select the animal or animals and invoke
				a popup menu item on one of the selected Animal
				Elements. 
				<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Right click on the Animal to get the Tracker
							popup menu
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select 'Add Template Events to Selected
							Animals' to bring up a selection window to
							select a Template
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Choose a Template containing the set of
							template events you wish to add the animal.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Indirectly Selecting Animals to Add Events and/or Animals</title>
			<para>
				To add a series of events and/or animals to the Premises
				you will need to select a Tag IdNumber file and invoke a
				popup menu item it.
				<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Right click on the Tag IdNumber File to get
							the Tracker popup menu.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Select 'Add Template Events to Premises' to
							bring up a selection window to select a
							Template.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Choose a Template containing the set of
							template events and the default animal type
							you wish to add the premises.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
