<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DockBook XML V4.5//EN" "../docbook-xml/docbookx.dtd" >
<chapter id="ch02">
	<title>Premises Model</title>
	<section>
		<title>Modeling the Animal Premises</title>
		<para>
			Computers can be thought of as mechanisms or containers for
			modeling aspects of the real world. The Tracker software
			application models the animals and event histories associated with
		    a livestock animal premises.  The Tracker application uses a
			document paradigm to model an animal premises.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Tracker Model Documents</title>
		<para>
			Whether it is word processing documents, spreadsheet documents, or
			presentation documents, today's computer users are most familiar with
			a type of software application that create and manipulate a
			document files to describe specific instances of information.  
		</para>
		<para>
			The Tracker enables users to create, transform and edit
			tracker model documents that represent specific
			Animal Premises. Model documents are displayed and
			manipulated with the various Tracker Editors, Wizards, and
			utilities. The attributes of the
			premises, the animals in the premises and the events
			associated with animals are specified within these model
			documents. 
		</para>
		<para>Tracker Model document files utilize a .tracker file
			extension to distinguish them from other types of files.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="ch02dataModel">
		<title>Tracker Data Model</title>
		<para>
			In the Tracker all activity centers around the manipulation of
			<emphasis>Tracker Model Documents</emphasis>. Understanding the 
			structure of Tracker Model documents is the easiest way to learn
			to use the information management facilities of the Tracker. </para>
		<para>
			All tracker model documents structurally conform to the <emphasis>Tracker Data
			Model</emphasis>. In the Tracker Data Model a single Premises contains
			zero or more animals. Each Animal must have at least one but
			may have more than one (identification) tags. Each Tag must
			have at least one but may have more than one associated
			events.
		</para>
		<para>
			In the figure below you will find a graphic representation
			of the core elements of the Tracker Data Model.
		
		<figure>
			<title>Tracker Data Model Core Elements</title>
			<graphic srccredit="Verticon, Inc., 2007"
				fileref="figures/coreDataModel3.png" />
		</figure>
		</para>
		<para> 
			<orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The core elements of the Data Model are depicted as the blue
			rectangles in the figure.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The notation within the elements are
			the attributes of the element.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The notation between the elements are
			the relationships of the elements.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
		<para>
			The following table offers a text explanation of the Element Relationships.
			<table frame='all'>
				<title>Core Elements of the Data Model</title>
				<tgroup cols='2' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
					<colspec colname='c1' />
					<colspec colname='c2' />
					<thead>
						<row>
							<entry>Element Name</entry>
							<entry>
								Relationship to other Elements
							</entry>
						</row>
					</thead>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry>Premises</entry>
							<entry>
								There is one premises in a document
							</entry>

						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Animal</entry>
							<entry>
								A premises can have zero or many animals
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Tag</entry>
							<entry>
								An Animal can have one or many tags
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry></entry>
							<entry>
								A Premises can have zero or many tags
								that are unassigned
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry>Event</entry>
							<entry>
								A Tag can have one or many events
							</entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</table>

		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
